- I wanna scrub in.
- We don't need you up here.
- You're a trauma surgeon, June.
- Without an effective treatment,
he'll die before she gets to know him.
You're solving a problem,
Dr. Leblanc,
that he may not want you to solve.
I don't understand.
I caught up with rent last month
- I'm sorry, Bashir.
- I have two bedrooms.
(TENSE MUSIC)
(MEDICAL MACHINES BEEPING)
(THEO TALKING IN THE DISTANCE)
It's a lot.
I want to help, I want this to work.
I know he's excited about retiring.
I want to help him get
ready for that, I do.
But I'm still working here now, alright?
For a few more months, anyways. So...
Can you just talk to him for me?
Yeah.
(SOFT PIANO MUSIC)
(RAIN DRIZZLING)
(CARS PASSING)
(THEO): Amira?
Everything alright?
My brother's not back?
No. He's still at work.
Is it okay if I wait for him?
Yeah. Of course.
(SIRENS)
(THEO): How was Amira this morning?
Tired. Sorry if she worried
you last night.
Grace wakes up like that
sometimes after a nightmare.
She's been displaced
so many times.
You're there for her,
that's all that matters.
I had to leave Lenny
on the side of the road.
- Who's Lenny?
- That's her car.
You have a car named Lenny?
Yes. And he's got, like,
a cracked engine block,
and he needs a new transmission
That's probably more
than the car costs.
I bought that car when I was
17 years old with my own money.
He's got me through
university, med school,
and an entire leg of
Sleater-Kinney's reunion tour
Hey. Excuse me.
- Are you a doctor?
- Yeah, how can I help?
You should've helped me
when you had the chance!
- (MAGS): Security!
- (MAN): Back off!
- Get off me!
- (LOU): Hey, hey, hey!
- We got this. We got this.
- Get off me!
(MAN GRUNTING)
Are you okay?
(THEO GROANING)
Here. Take this.
(PANTING)
(THEME MUSIC)
- Synced and corrected by martythecrazy -
- www.addic7ed.com -
I know I'm late, sir.
Won't happen again.
Actually, you're right on time.
No, it's just Theo
this morning, I was...
Why did you choose
emergency medicine, Dr. Leblanc?
I know for a fact you could've
had your pick of residencies.
- Why this one?
- Uh...
Because in Emerg, you can't
just be good at one thing.
You gotta be the best at everything.
And are you?
Well, I...
I definitely have things to work on.
But...
Do you know what the minimum expectation
of patients treated per shift is?
- Twenty.
- And...
What do you think your average is?
- Less.
- Fifteen.
You're saying I need
to move faster. I can do that.
I'm saying there's a reason
you don't.
You spend too much time per case.
Your patient histories
are more comprehensive
than any other resident.
Well, isn't that why
I catch as much as I do?
You catch too much.
You actively look for problems to solve.
What we do here is present tense.
The drive-through
instead of fine dining.
We treat what they came for.
We admit them if they need it,
cut them loose if they don't.
You've never raised this before
Well, now that you're reaching
the end of your second year,
it's a good time to
correct any bad habits
before they become a pattern.
Which is why you're going to
be evaluated today, by me.
Who do we have waiting
this morning, Claire?
Uh, we gotta head lac,
we've got an ankle sprain,
and a senior with a fever.
I'll start with the fever.
Here you go!
(TENSE MUSIC)
Mm. What I wouldn't give
for a large cup of coffee.
Uh, Doctor? Uh, doctor...?
- Hamed.
- Hamed. Javier.
Um... My wife Maria, she's got this flu.
Javy, mi amor.
I know, I'm just explaining.
Um, and...
We just wanted to make sure there
isn't anything we should be doing.
We're headed up to OB,
so no need to bother the doctor.
No, it's not a problem,
They'll listen to the baby
and probably ask you to take
it easy for a couple of days.
(ELEVATOR DINGS)
- Okay. Thank you.
- You're welcome.
And ask to check out that rash.
(THEO): Thank you.
Thanks.
Yeah, it's broken.
Hey, thanks
for coming to my rescue.
Did they find out who the guy was?
Supposedly he was waiting
for a doctor,
and I guess he got tired of waiting.
And just needed someone
to take it out on?
The way you jumped in, uh...
Guessing you've had to do
that kind of thing before?
Doesn't mean you get used to it.
Well, I've never been in a fight.
I wouldn't exactly
call that a fight.
A stranger came out of nowhere
and punched you in the face.
- That's...
- Twice.
And I didn't do anything
to try to stop him.
I just... froze.
Hey, I can... I can cover your
patients if you want to go home.
I don't have to leave.
Well, if you just want
to take a break for an hour.
No, I'm good. Thanks, Bash.
Thanks for the coffee.
Your surgical attending
has you transwriting charts?
Sutures, cyst drainage,
foreign body removal, more sutures.
If he's in a really good
mood, I get to suction.
They call it paying your dues.
So I've been told.
I know Singh's work
takes precedence
over anything you pick
up down here, but...
if you get a second,
I have a woman in curtain
four with a runny nose.
Don't tell me she needs suction
Actually, it's a bit of a mystery.
Been going on three years.
No signs of infection.
(MAGS): Okay, Mrs. Willis.
Well, based on what I can see
here, I think it's just a flu.
So, I'm gonna put you in an IV
to rehydrate you, and give you
acetaminophen for the fever.
I worried
when the dizzy spells got worse.
The dizzy spells, you didn't, you
didn't mention that to triage.
Oh, that nurse was so busy,
I didn't want to bother.
No, that's no bother.
How long has that been going on?
A few weeks.
My doctor says it's a neural thing?
Mm... And are you diabetic?
- Mm-hmm.
- Okay.
Is it possible he called
it peripheral neuropathy?
Um... That sounds right.
I... I wrote the name down.
- But I...
- Well, if it's neuropathy,
an inhibitor may not be
the best course of action
I'm gonna do some tests, okay?
Okay, thank you.
Of course.
(SOFT MUSIC)
(MAN): Excuse me, are you a doctor?
- Back off!
- (LOU): We got this! We got this!
(BASHIR): Are you okay?
(SIRENS)
Mrs. Rawana? Hi, I'm Dr. Curtis.
I hear you have quite the runny nose.
I didn't want to come in,
but my daughter made me after
it started getting worse.
Take a breath.
Sit up.
It's getting worse?
I'm used to getting up
with a wet pillow.
The last few days it's been
more like a pond than a puddle.
Mm.
Okay, and you've spoken to
your family doctor about this?
She says I have bad allergies,
and sent me to an ear, nose and throat
doctor who said the same thing.
They put me on this medication.
Diphenhydramine.
It makes me drowsy.
What's the point in feeling that
way if it's not even helping?
Well, I'm gonna have a look, okay?
Can you open your mouth?
Is your family from the Caribbean?
Jamaica, but my parents met here.
I was born in Trinidad.
My husband, too.
Your parents must be so proud of you.
Beautiful black woman.
Big city doctor.
No pain?
Anyway...
I'm sure you tell them the same
thing our daughter tells us.
Be proud, be supportive,
but do it from the sidelines.
How long have you had
that bump on your collarbone?
Is it something
I should be concerned about?
Not necessarily, but I'll...
I'll have a closer look.
Can I get a CT and labs
on Mrs. Willis?
Mrs. Willis, that's the
elderly lady with the flu?
Yeah, she's having dizzy spells.
We need to call her GP for a history.
I won't let it slow me down.
How's doctor Hunter today?
He's had better mornings.
Doctor Hamed?
Hey, is everything okay?
OB is very busy today.
They said they could see
us, but not for a while.
Maria's very tired,
I just want her to be seen.
We were wondering if you could
check her and the baby out?
No problem. Follow me.
Blood pressure's normal.
You must be getting excited.
Over the moon.
- How many weeks?
- Thirty-one.
And tell me about your symptoms.
We spent the weekend
at a friend's cottage up north.
I started to feel nauseous
on the car ride back.
- And this was yesterday?
- Uh-huh.
I thought it was car sickness,
but this morning I had a fever.
And then we started to worry that
the baby wasn't moving as much,
but um, we couldn't be sure, so...
Let's take a look.
Sorry, I know it's a little cold.
(HEARTBEAT ON ULTRASOUND)
That sound's good, right?
Yes. Very good.
Do you know the gender of the baby?
Because I think I can tell.
No spoilers!
(Laughing) Sorry, we've
just waited this long,
and we want to go the distance.
I completely understand.
Well, everything seems normal,
baby seems healthy,
blood pressure is good,
so you can sit up.
But there is one more
thing I should look at.
Um, how long have you had
that rash on your arm?
I scraped myself on the dock
at the cottage,
climbing down to the
water to go for a swim.
- Any pain?
- A bit.
But I bruise easily.
That's all it is, right?
Uh, we just need to make sure.
I need to make an incision,
prep the Lidocaine.
Are, are you worried
about something?
If there's an infection, we just
need to know how to manage it.
It's okay.
- Hi.
- Hi, love.
- Do you feel anything?
- No.
- You may want to look away.
- Oh, he's the squeamish one.
(CHUCKLES) I have other skills.
Ah. Okay.
Oh. What is that?
(JAVIER): Is there a problem?
Hey. Are you okay?
I was gonna ask you
the same thing.
Bishop's putting me
through the wringer today.
What's wrong?
I'm a waiting on rush labs.
I have a 31 weeks pregnant woman
who seems to have a
very serious infection.
31 weeks? Why is she not in OB?
They were swamped, so the
couple came to me directly.
You know, I'd offer to
help, but I'm just...
I'm trying to stay focused because...
Don't worry about it.
What kind of infection?
(OMINOUS MUSIC)
- Dr. Bishop?
- Yeah, what is it?
I've got a 36-year-old woman,
31 weeks pregnant
and presenting with
flesh-eating bacteria.
(OMINOUS MUSIC)
I have never seen necrotizing
fasciitis in a pregnant woman.
Neither have I. Have you
treated this infection before?
No sir, but I have seen
numerous cases of gangrene.
Then you know
we have to move fast.
You've started her on antibiotics?
600 milligrams of IV Clinda
and 2 grams of IV Ancef.
She's already on fluids.
How'd she contract it?
She scraped herself on a dock.
- And the baby?
- Fetal heart rate's normal.
Sepsis from infection can cause
stillbirth or miscarriage.
Well, it's presenting on her upper
arm, just above the elbow,
so hopefully we can control
it and limit spread.
We'll do an MRI,
see if that's the case.
And then what, Dr. Hamed?
Assuming it hasn't spread,
what are her options?
Uh, radical debridement.
But that means putting her under.
Extremely risky for a pregnant woman.
The only other option
is amputation,
and she'll need a general
anaesthetic either way.
Well, the decision has to be
the patient's ultimately.
I'll reach out
to infectious diseases,
start a dialogue with a surgeon.
I'll talk to Maria.
Are... Are you talking about
cutting off my arm?
If you choose this option, yes.
(MARIA LAUGHING)
And this other option,
debridement?
- It means I get to keep it?
- Yes.
But you have to understand,
amputation increases the
likelihood that we get everything.
Debridment means cutting out
only the infected tissue,
but the risk of the bacteria
spreading are higher.
I should have never
gone for that swim.
- Maria, don't say that.
- No, Javier, you can't.
The infection is dangerous
and aggressive.
Am I not already exposed?
Let's hope not.
And we cannot take that chance.
And these antibiotics,
are you sure they won't harm our baby?
Your baby is safe for now.
The best predictor of the baby
doing well is you doing well.
Which means...
we need to decide.
How is this happening now?
We've tried for so long for this baby!
That's all we've thought
about for years!
A surgeon is coming
to talk to you shortly.
But any delay will put your life
and your baby's life in danger.
- This is crazy. We need time...
- Debridement.
I want the debridement.
No, M-Maria,
I want to hold our child
in my arms.
Rock my baby to sleep.
(SOFT MUSIC)
Annette Rawana, 55-years-old,
persistent runny nose.
If you look really closely,
you can actually see
the hole in her dura.
There. Yeah. Turns out
cerebrospinal fluid
has been leaking from her
brain into her sinuses.
She's seen her GP multiple
times about this,
even an ENT who thought it was mucus.
But it's not.
It's brain fluid.
Is this a genetic
malformation of the dura?
Nope. I found a small
deformity on her collarbone.
It's not the cause of the
leak, but it is a clue.
So turns out three years
ago, she had a minor fall.
Yeah. She was at the park with her
grandson, fractures her clavicle.
The bone didn't heal properly.
Not uncommon in a patient
over 50. But...
There was a small basal skull fracture
that they missed at the time,
resulting in a dural defect.
It's been asymptomatic until now.
If you hadn't caught this,
she would have had severe
seizures, or even meningitis.
Tom, check this out.
Three-year runny nose. Total mystery.
ENT thought it was mucus.
Wow, you can barely
see the hole on the scan.
Nice catch.
I'll put it on the
neuro-board, and book an OR.
(SCOFFS)
Oh come on, he said nice catch.
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
That's a good look for a doctor.
Just so you know, the police
are charging the gentleman.
Turns out he has a history
of anger problems.
- Is it broken?
- I'm fine.
Ah. We take assault against
our staff very seriously.
Even if they are only here temporarily.
I noticed you hadn't submitted or
the full-time pediatrics position.
Applications are open
for two more weeks.
Wife didn't go for it, huh?
Thank you.
Figured it's more of an in-person
conversation next time I was home.
Smart man.
These things never work out
unless you're both same page.
(THEO): How do you feel today, Eva?
- (EVA): Okay.
- That's good.
(WOMAN): Eva was diagnosed with
epilepsy a few months ago.
We've been learning to manage
the seizures but this morning
she wasn't herself, then
started throwing up.
We weren't sure if it was
related to the epilepsy.
Is purple
your favourite colour, Eva?
- Mm-hmm.
- Yeah?
My daughter's favourite
is pink sparkly rainbow.
Okay. It's good.
What happened to your nose?
To my nose? Uh...
I told a lie,
so it grew like Pinocchio's.
You're worried you
might've missed a seizure?
Maybe while she was asleep.
She doesn't wear the helmet at night
If she hit her head, a concussion
would explain the nausea.
I keep a detailed journal
of all her seizures,
and she's never had one
in her sleep before.
Couldn't the vomiting
be related to the flu?
It's possible,
but she isn't running a fever.
Eva, do you remember bumping
your head last night?
- Mm-mm.
- No?
Okay, I'm gonna take a look
while you play with that.
There you go.
Okay.
Well, I don't see any
evidence of head injury,
but we'll run some tests
to get a sense of whether
or not these symptoms
have anything to do with epilepsy.
This is all so new for us.
Well, we have a great
social workers here,
if you need support while
you're adjusting to it all.
Our church family's been amazing.
Sending meals, offering rides.
They've really shown up for us.
Well, a strong community
can make a lot of difference.
My Dad's a pastor in Sudbury.
I go every Sunday when I'm home.
You mentioned testing.
What kind, exactly?
A CT and an EEG.
But it won't hurt, we're just gonna
take a picture of your brain.
What are the chances
the pastor's son is our doctor?
A nurse will be by
to get you when it's time, okay?
I'm gonna get that off your hands, okay?
Thank you very much. (THEO CHUCKLES)
(SOFT MUSIC)
(MAGS): Why haven't I seen the
CT results for Mrs. Willis?
- She hasn't been.
- Why not?
Because she doesn't need it.
Sir, she has peripheral neuropathy
and I just wanted to find the cause
I read her chart.
She came in with flu.
That doesn't require a CAT scan.
Her GP has her on an SSRI instead
of treating the nerve pain.
Well, maybe there's a very
good reason for that.
Maybe they tried antiseizure drugs
for her neuropathic pain
and they didn't work
No, I called for a history.
They haven't.
- I can help her.
- You have helped her.
You treated her dehydration and fever.
Now you send her back to her
primary care physician,
and you help someone else.
That's the system.
I'm on track
for my twenty patients.
Have you caught up on your charts?
Have you even take a lunch?
The extra time you spend digging
in, it has to come from somewhere.
I don't mind sacrificing lunch
if it means I can help a
patient solve a problem.
This job's about balance, doctor.
See everything, solve what's necessary.
I wouldn't push her if I didn't
think she could handle it.
I didn't say anything.
Hey, how was your lunch with
your son the other day?
(SIGHING) Brief.
(CELL PHONE CHIMING)
- Hi.
- (BASHIR): Hey. Where are you?
Home.
You mean the old apartment?
If you know where I am,
why are you asking?
The building manager saw you.
Did you...
Did you go back to see Daneesha?
No.
Amira, you can't just go
roaming around the city.
I need to know where you are
and where you're going.
I didn't mean to!
I just got on the bus without thinking.
It's not a big deal, okay?
Okay. Okay.
We only just got used to it here.
It's the first place that felt like home
since we left Mama and Baba's.
I know it's hard, Habibti, but...
we have to keep moving forward. Mm?
(SOFT PIANO MUSIC)
Can you get to Theo's on your own?
Yes.
I'll be fine. I'll see you later, okay?
Okay.
Are you okay?
We tried to conceive
for two years.
Three failed rounds of in-vitro.
I took a night job,
Maria took extra freelance work, and...
Every single time a cycle didn't work,
and she would get the news,
and it destroyed her.
And then, and then it worked.
We're gonna have a baby.
And now all I can think
is, is it all worth it?
Hey, it will be.
Okay? As soon as she's done,
we'll get her into an MRI
to make sure the bacteria hasn't spread.
Thank you.
(SOMBER PIANO MUSIC)
Really?
Well, if you're sure that's
all I can do, then fine.
- Who died?
- Lenny.
My car.
He would need a new engine.
Maybe it's time for an upgrade.
Something awesome, like a Mustang.
I don't want a Mustang,
I want Lenny.
I hear Singh and Duncan
figured out what was going on
- with your patient's runny nose?
- Something like that.
Play the long game, Dr. Curtis.
Suck it up and be excellent.
When the dust settles,
you'll be miles beyond them.
What was that about?
Some unsolicited career advice
from a woman who hasn't exactly
cracked the glass ceiling.
That's not fair,
she's an attending.
Maybe she's right where she wants to be.
Oh yeah? Stuck as Bishop's second?
He's not exactly easy to please.
I'm not interested
in pleasing anyone.
- I know, I know.
- And I don't need her advice.
Alright, alright.
Alright? Everything
that I have in my life,
- I got...
- on my own, I know.
You know, on my own.
I'm just saying, maybe, you know,
she's legitimately trying to help you.
Yeah? Like Bishop's
trying to help you?
He's saying I over-diagnose.
He's got me doubting my whole approach.
Don't let them
get in your head, Mags.
How did you manage this?
Stupidity, mostly.
Casualties from my
last night of freedom.
Getting married, or going to jail?
- Work, actually.
- Mm.
I fly back to the tar sands
tonight
- for a three-month stint.
- Hmm.
And this is how you celebrate?
Let's just say, when you launch
yourself off the back of the truck
to catch a football, best
to watch for the tailgate.
Let me guess, there was a
little bit of alcohol involved?
Tell me this isn't gonna
make me miss my flight.
If I don't go tonight,
I'll miss the whole week.
Hold this for me.
(COUGHING)
Well, you'll need stitches,
and a tetanus shot.
Do you have any other pain?
Just the hangover.
Any neck pain?
No.
- (MAN CLEARS HIS THROAT)
- So, three months,
That's a pretty long stint.
You like working in bursts like that?
Easier to focus if it's all in.
Then when I'm off, I can actually relax.
Hmm. And you can do that?
Just shut off and relax?
Yeah it's like,
as soon as I get off the plane,
see my friends, my dog, and
it's like a switch flips.
Move your jaw for me.
Alright. I'll get you started on an IV.
Is that necessary?
If you don't want to feel like
crap when you're flying, yes.
I'll come back in a few minutes
to suture that gash, and then
we'll get you out of here.
Thanks, doc.
(MACHINES BEEPING RAPIDLY)
What happened?
She threw up again, then her eyes
started rolling back in her head!
- Heart rate's 210.
- (FATHER): Another seizure?
2.5 megs of adenosine.
Prepare to cardiovert.
25 Joules, synchronized.
(DEVICE CHARGING UP)
(RAPID BEEPING)
It isn't working. Okay, charging.
- (AUTOMATED VOICE): Shock advised.
- Everybody clear?
Shocking.
(RAPID BEEPING)
Come on baby, wake up.
Why isn't she moving?
What else can you do?
Okay. Raising to 50,
shocking again.
Charging. Everybody clear!
- (AUTOMATED VOICE): Shock advised.
- Shocking.
(RAPID BEEPING)
(BEEPING STOPS)
(FATHER): Oh, thank God.
Hi, Eva.
Do you know where you are?
I threw up.
If there's one place you're allowed
to throw up, that's the hospital.
- What happened to her?
- She's gonna be fine.
We're gonna need to run more tests
but it looks like Eva had an episode
of supraventricular tachycardia.
It's when the heart suddenly
starts beating too fast.
Is that part of her epilepsy?
It is a common side effect,
and likely explains the
symptoms from this morning.
Could this be a one-time thing?
Unfortunately,
SVT isn't normally isolated.
So you should be prepared for
this to happen from time to time.
Does that mean she now has
to deal with seizures,
and a heart problem?
Do we have to bring her back
here every time it happens?
No. There are interventions
to help with episodes at home.
Hey. We're gonna get through this.
We're only given as much
as we can handle, right?
Yeah.
What interventions?
Someone needs to teach us what to do.
Mama, I'm thirsty.
- (KNOCKING)
- (BASHIR): You wanted to see me, sir?
Yeah. Our pregnant patient...
Mm-hmm.
Radiology sent her results
directly to me.
(SIGHING)
The debridement didn't stop
the bacteria from spreading.
There's infected tissue
deeper in the shoulder.
Which means amputation
is no longer an option.
We need to get her back in for
another debridement immediately
or she'll go into septic shock.
(SIGHING) They knew the risks.
All we can do now is deal
with what's in front of us.
Sir, the baby might not
withstand a second debridement.
And if the infection spreads
to the uterus and fetus,
then miscarriage and stillbirth
are very real possibilities.
We need to move fast,
and we're out of conservative
options, which leaves us with...
A C-section.
Get the baby out safely,
and then right into another debridement.
- She's 31 weeks?
- Yes. Viable.
Maybe not for the mother.
Delaying debridement for a
caesarean poses a major risk.
Her inflammatory response could
trigger multiple organ failure.
If we don't deliver, the
baby won't make it.
Save the baby or save the mother.
Save both. But they need
to pick who goes first.
- I'll call OB.
- No, we can't send her upstairs.
It's protocol not to let
an infection like nec fasc
anywhere near that ward.
I'll arrange for an OR.
Sir, I've debrided necrotic
tissue before
We'll let the surgeons handle it.
- I was a trauma surgeon.
- I'm aware of that Dr. Hamed,
but you are not one now.
You're an emergency resident here.
These parents have sacrificed
so much for their baby.
I need to make sure they're
around to raise it.
That's what you've been doing
all day.
Stay with the husband
during the procedure.
He'll need someone to walk him
through what's happening.
If they thought they had a
tough choice earlier...
No.
- Javier...
- No. He's asking us
to choose between your life and
the baby's. We can't do that.
- I can't do that.
- Not choose, Javier.
Just prioritize.
Save the baby.
Maria, but wait
Listen...
Save the baby.
Maria. Let's talk about this.
Okay?
I can't lose this baby, Javier.
I won't.
You know what this means to me.
Okay Maria, but you could die.
I love this baby.
(SOMBER MUSIC)
It's already a part of me,
and I need to protect it.
I need you to be strong,
and there for our baby either way.
And I need to hear you say it.
I need you to promise me.
Of course.
Of course I will.
I promise.
(CRYING)
I love you.
Do the C-section, Dr. Hamed.
We'll get ready.
One more thing before I go?
Am I having a girl,
or am I having a boy?
You'll see for yourself
when you wake up.
(SOFT MUSIC)
Has cardiology
been by to see you yet?
They taught me about
vagal maneuvers she can do
to slow her heart down,
and when to know if she
needs to be brought in.
It might not be forever.
Some kids do outgrow their seizures.
If you're asking me to wait
for a miracle,
that's Luke's department.
He's in the chapel now.
Oh. I can sit with her if
you'd like to go join him.
I pray too, Dr. Hunter.
But I do it with my eyes wide open.
And I only ask for the courage
to be strong enough for Eva,
to give my daughter what she needs.
She's lucky to have you.
And I'm lucky to have her.
Promise me you'll keep this clean,
and you'll get a doctor
to get the clips out.
You're a lifesaver.
(COUGHING)
- You feeling okay?
- Yeah.
Just dry mouth.
I'll grab some water on my way out.
(COUGHING)
I think we should
take your temperature.
I swear doc, I'm fine.
Still probably, you know maybe
just a little hungover.
(COUGHING VIOLENTLY)
- Okay. Okay.
- What?!
Take this. Sit down.
Sit back down.
What, uh... What's happening?
Alright. Take this off. Lie down.
It's gonna be cold.
Pleural effusion.
You've got water on your lungs.
What? Why?
My guess would be
pulmonary embolism.
When you injured your leg,
a blood clot formed and
travelled to your lungs.
You're gonna need to start
anti-coagulants immediately.
I'm... I'm gonna be okay?
Well, we caught it early, which is good,
but you're definitely not
gonna make that flight.
I'll be right back.
What?
(BASHIR): Our obstetrician
will deliver the baby
with the help of our general surgeon.
There's a team from NICU on standby.
Once they get the baby
out, the general surgeon
will debride the remaining
infected tissue.
Let's get moving.
We're already on borrowed time.
Making the first incision.
(MACHINES BEEPING STEADILY)
And into the fascia.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC)
Scissors. Thank you.
Suction.
(SUCTIONING)
One, two, three, stretch.
Lower end.
Lower end out, retract her out.
I've got the baby's head.
Give me pressure.
Give me pressure! Again!
Baby's flat, let's be quick.
(JUNE): Looks like a uterine
artery has been clipped.
I'm on it.
Nice work, doctor. Stay close.
There's not much time.
Come on, let's go.
I'll start bagging.
Get the monitors up.
Chest is moving. Turn the O2 to 100.
What? Wait, what's wrong?
What's happening?
The baby's premature. There
are added steps to be taken.
The heart rate's 47.
Prepare to intubate.
What, the baby's not breathing?
The heart rate's too low.
They're working to bring it up.
(TUBES HISSING)
(STEADY BEEPING)
Starting compressions.
(BREATHING HEAVILY) Oh, my God.
Pause compressions.
We're good. Let's get the baby to NICU.
Heart rate's stable.
(RAPID BEEPING)
What the...
What about the alarms?
What's he looking at?
What's happening to Maria?
She, um... She's in respiratory
distress and septic shock.
But Javier, I promise you,
our surgeons will do whatever they can.
Go to NICU.
Your baby's not out of the woods yet.
There could be choices to be made.
What about Maria?
There's nothing you can
do for Maria right now.
I know you want to be in two
places at once, but you can't.
I'll stay with Maria.
And as soon as there's news of
any kind, I'll come get you.
Go see your baby, Javier.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC)
I heard you caught
a pulmonary embolism.
- I noti...
- Nice work.
I noticed him coughing, and I should've
investigated it sooner, but...
All I could hear was
your voice in my head.
Telling you what?
That I'm... That I'm focusing
on all the wrong things.
That's your voice, Mags. Not mine.
This job...
is all I've ever wanted.
Then find the way to be the doctor
I need you to be.
(SOFT MUSIC)
Good night, Dr. Leblanc.
(BABIES CRYING)
(SOFT PIANO MUSIC)
Maria?
She's going to be okay.
(SHARP INHALE)
(BABY CRYING)
It's a beautiful baby.
(SOBBING)
Dr. Curtis.
Have you ever...
wanted to just burn it all down?
Instead of sucking it up?
All the time.
Have you? Ever?
Once or twice.
Was it worth it?
The only one who got burned
was me.
Well, I...
I mean, anytime you
have a patient for me,
I'm interested. So...
I'll keep that in mind.
(SOFT MUSIC)
It looks like we stopped
the infection.
Your latest MRI was clear.
You are so brave.
You're so strong.
The baby?
Baby? I took a video...
- of our little girl.
- A little girl?
She looks just like her papa.
(LAUGHING)
She's four pounds, three ounces,
but she's a fighter, like her mom.
(TOW-TRUCK WHIRRING)
(SOFT MUSIC)
I was looking for you.
Listen, I...
may have been a little
short with you today.
Not punching back, Theo,
that's nothing to be ashamed of.
I've never punched back.
Not in any part of my life.
Amira went home today.
Our old apartment,
without even knowing
where she was going.
You know, she's been through
so much, and, uh...
I don't know what I'm doing.
None of us do.
(SOFT MUSIC)
Long road ahead for that family.
And all so that, in 18 years time,
the kid can resent them,
and they can wonder
if everything they went
through today was worth it.
Jed.
Is that really how you feel?
No.
(SOFT MUSIC)
(AMIRA): What happened to
getting me something small?
I changed my mind.
We both deserve it.
(TRAFFIC PASSING)
(PEOPLE LAUGHING IN THE DISTANCE)
Did you know that you were
born with a full head of hair?
And you worried just like that
when you were little, too.
I'm sorry I lost my
temper with you today.
I'm so proud of how you're handling
everything that we're going through.
Mama used to get mad at me
for playing with my hair.
Said it would all fall
out and I would go bald.
She started braiding it so I would stop
I could braid for you, too?
(LAUGHING)
Mama said braids
were way harder than stitches.
I keep dreaming about her.
- Are they good dreams?
- Most of them.
Why don't you like it when I
talk about Mama and Baba?
Is that what you think? No.
No.
Yella. Time for class.
- You'll wait?
- I'm not going anywhere.
(SOFT PIANO MUSIC)
(SIGHING)
(HIGH-PITCHED RINGING)
(EERIE MUSIC)
(HEAVY BREATHING)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC)
- Synced and corrected by martythecrazy -
- www.addic7ed.com -