When I was your age, I had to spend
the night in a hospital too.
Lots of times, actually.
It's difficult when you come
home for such a short time.
I know it's hard. But we're here now.
You should make the most of it.
I can't accept this.
It's a gift for Eid, tradition.
Okay? How's the place?
It's fine.
I don't have much
privacy, but it's a bed.
You haven't heard from
the police again I hope?
No. You?
Nothing.
Hopefully they've forgotten me now.
And what about work? Have
you been able to find any?
I did. I did.
English, Amira.
If he needs money,
maybe he needs food?
Amira, you know I'm working, huh?
What's the story they told?
So many people came for Mama's Maqlubeh
that we finished it all?
Baba had to bring more lamb?
You remember that? You were so young.
We should be celebrating.
What? We went to prayers.
I got you new clothes.
I wish they were still here.
I know.
I want to come to the hospital with you.
- Amira.
- It's Saturday.
I will be quiet. I won't move.
I'll do my homework.
I have a lot of homework, Bash.
Amira, it's not the kind of place
people go for no reason, okay?
I have a reason. I want
to be with you today.
Okay.
Hello, Dr. Leblanc.
Force of habit. I'm sorry.
I know I've missed a few appointments.
I know.
All you're supposed to do
is see me twice a year.
Yeah, I know.
You're avoiding me, Magalie.
No, I'm... I'm busy.
Your rhythm's normal now,
but there was a flag on
your remote monitoring.
- Arrhythmia?
- Mm.
- More than one flag?
- Three. You didn't feel them?
We replace a pacemaker every six years.
I've had this one almost that long.
It's probably just a glitch.
Humour me. How've you been feeling?
Totally at odds with whatever
report that thing sent you.
I'm fine. If there was anything wrong,
I'd be feeling dizziness,
shortness of breath, chest pain.
Yeah, yeah, you're a doctor, I get it.
I'd still like to do a
stress test to be sure.
Half an hour. That's all I need.
I've got to go to work. Next week?
What do I have to do here, Mags?
Get Bishop to make you
my cardiology fellow?
I'll be back, I promise.
Do you ever not start early?
Oh! Ah! You need to tell me if you see
the girl with snakes in her veins.
Hey Charlie. Did you come
for a needle exchange?
He was polling all of triage,
asking about snakes.
Scared a couple people so they
said to put him in Exam 4.
Okay. I'll get a nurse to start fluids.
He seems a bit off his baseline.
Good morning, Dr. Curtis.
Lou? Are you two a thing?
Like a secret work thing?
Please learn boundaries.
Fast start today, we
have a GSW coming in,
33-year-old male, ETA 8 minutes.
I need blood. I need bodies.
There's a found down on the way in too.
Dr. Hamed takes the found down. Dr.
Curtis, Dr. Leblanc with the GSW.
Any info on the patient?
Elderly woman in cardiac arrest.
That's all I've got.
Oh and good news. I'll
be your attending today.
What? It was a scheduling mess up.
Meaning you went in and messed it up?
Lena Joseph, 85 years old,
VF arrest. Mailman saw her
in the living room floor and
broke through the front window.
She's obviously been down for
some time, she looks dehydrated.
12 minutes CPR. Defib'd
twice and two doses of epi.
No pulse. She's still in VFIB.
Okay, charging the defibrillator, 200J,
unsynchronized. Everybody clear.
Shock advised.
Start compressions right away.
Do we know how long she was lying
here before anybody found her?
Could've been days. The
mailman said she lives alone.
There's a daughter, but
she wasn't around.
Two minutes of CPR and
then a pulse check.
Will Marsh, BP 80 over
60, heart rate 110.
They were held up at
gunpoint outside a bank.
Will pushed me out of the way.
I was handing over my purse
and the guy shot anyway!
Okay, stay here, alright?
Stay right here.
One, two, three.
Will, can you feel your arms and legs?
What do we have?
Single penetrating bullet
wound to the abdomen.
Husband and wife report
hearing one shot fired.
Has he been persistently hypotensive?
80's four over 62.
Let's log roll him to
check for other wounds.
On three. One, two, three.
Stop! Please
Will, let me know where it hurts!
- No exit wound.
- One, two, three.
The bullet is still inside, sir.
What does the bullet rule say, Dr.
Leblanc?
The bullet wound seen on imaging
should always be an even number.
LOC decreasing. Get him
some blood and TXA.
- FAST positive.
- Let's get an AP,
abdomen and chest,
see if we can find the
bullet or fragments.
Let's roll him, on three.
One, two, three.
Give me a sec.
Will?
Ma'am, you can't be in here right now.
Lucy, Will's a fighter! Okay?
We need to figure out the path
the bullet took when it
went through his body
Dr. Bishop? Looks like the bullet
is lodged against his pancreas.
The best thing you can do for
Will is to give us space to work.
I'll come and explain everything after.
Find out how long OR needs
for an emergency lap.
On it.
While you're filling the wife in,
- get a full medical history.
- Copy.
Recharging defib.
Stop compressions. Everybody clear.
Shock advised.
Okay, I've got a pulse.
She's waking up!
Mrs. Joseph?
It's good to have you back with us.
This isn't right.
It's okay. You were
under cardiac arrest,
but we were able to revive you.
You were supposed to let me die.
- Synced and corrected by martythecrazy -
- www.addic7ed.com -
- Well, that's a new one.
Charlie's in the vents? Going where?
Pharmacy, maybe.
He's out of luck, all the
narcotics are locked up.
Should I call the cops, Dr. Bishop?
Or the fire department?
Not much point until we can find him.
We've known Charlie for years.
He's harmless.
Best to try and coax him down
before we have to take
more drastic action.
I connected with Lena
Joseph's daughter, Erin.
She's on her way.
How did she react?
Like she found out her
mother almost died.
Not sure there's a standard response.
I don't know how you'd be
able to forgive yourself
for something like that.
We don't know the whole story.
Well, we know she wasn't there,
and her mother was alone.
I've learned to not let what
happens here affect me personally.
Or maybe it's what makes
you a good doctor.
Miles, this is Doctor Hunter.
You can call me Theo.
What seems to be the problem, pal?
Persistent erection.
That can happen.
You here by yourself?
He didn't wanna give
us his mom's number.
Okay.
How long it's been going on?
Could you give us a minute? Thank you.
Four hours.
It hurts.
Okay, Miles, you're going
to be fine, but...
four hours is a long time. You
wanna tell me what's going on?
I was supposed to meet
this girl after school.
So you took something.
I found some of my dad's old pills.
And that's why you didn't
want us to call your mom.
She'd freak! We don't talk
about this kind of stuff.
It might resolve with ice
and pseudoephedrine.
If plan A works, we don't
have to call your mom.
What's plan B?
Let's cross that bridge
if we come to it. Okay?
Are you my mother's doctor?
- Yes. Bashir Hamed.
- Hi.
They said that you were out of town?
At a month-long training
program for work.
But I drove straight back
here as soon as they called.
I saw her just before I left.
How could I have missed
her being so ill?
She was extremely dehydrated
when she was brought in.
Malnourished.
She hadn't had any food
or water for days.
I stocked her fridge.
I even tried to set her
up with a meal program.
Has she been...
forgetful? Or...
I don't think so. Why?
It's possible that she stopped
eating and drinking...
on purpose.
No. My mother would never do that.
- Lucy?
- Hmm?
Will's being prepped for an emergency
surgery to remove the bullet.
But you said it's been
lodged in his abdomen?
Yes. Which caused significant bleeding.
Surgeons will be able to
tell us if there's damage
to his organs once they take it out.
Do you want to sit down? Please.
Um...
The guy, he smelled like cigarettes.
And at first, I thought he was
just waiting to use the machine.
I just wanted to stop for cash.
And if I didn't, none of
this would be happening.
Police told us they
arrested the shooter.
Now he asked if I was doing okay.
He's lying there...
Bleeding...
and he's asking if I'm okay?
You found yourself a good one.
I don't deserve him.
I'm sure that's not true.
But Will needs you now.
I'd like to ask you a few questions
about his medical history.
It'll help us treat him.
Let's start with medication.
Is he taking anything regularly?
Mom? Your doctor thinks
that you may have stopped
eating on purpose?
I told him there's no
way that could be true.
But are you not feeling well?
Have you lost your appetite?
I didn't want you to
have to deal with this.
Are you saying he's right?
I'm so sorry, honey.
The cleaner was coming Monday.
He was going to find me.
- You tried to die?
- More like...
I stopped trying to live.
Food. Water.
My pills.
I had it all planned out
I don't understand Why.
Why would you do this?
I'm old, Erin.
Everything hurts.
I wanted to control this.
Go on my terms.
While I still could.
How could you be thinking
like this and not tell me?
Please, honey.
Try to understand.
You know how awful it was when Dad went.
So I'm just supposed to be
okay with losing you too?
No. I can't hear this.
I can't hear this right now.
She taught high school physics.
She always pushed me to
be rational, ordered,
even as a kid.
I've never heard her sound like that.
Are you sure she hasn't been
struggling with depression?
It's been tough since Dad passed,
but that's been two years now.
I thought she was fine.
That is not her.
At her age, there could be some
underlying neurological condition.
I'd like to send her to get a
CT scan and cognitive testing.
Something like dementia can cause
extreme personality changes.
Yes. Please.
Please do everything you can.
- I will.
- Thank you.
Anything?
Should I try more...
I think we're beyond manual labour.
Time for plan B.
You never said what that was.
We drain it with a needle. Don't worry.
It sounds worse than it is.
We use freezing.
Ugh, can we wait a little longer?
I think if you call my mom, she's
definitely gonna call my dad.
He moved to San Francisco
after they split.
Well, I don't live in the
same city as my kids,
and I'd still want to know
what's going on with them.
Do you visit them?
Mine doesn't.
And now...
my mom's gonna blame him
because they were his pills.
Which is only gonna give him
more reason not to visit.
Okay.
We can give it a bit longer.
Hey.
Are you avoiding me?
First we can't be seen together,
and now I can't smile at you?
Look. When I see you, I smile.
I can't help it.
I just don't want everyone knowing
our business. Okay? So...
Or is it that you're embarrassed
to be dating the help?
Would you stop talking
about yourself like that?
If that's not the problem, then what is?
You really wanna do this now?
Maybe we shouldn't do it at all.
Is that the CT on your found down?
Mrs. Joseph. Radiology
reported it's clear.
Next step is to order a psych eval.
You know you're going to
need my sign-off for that.
She has chronic kidney disease,
but good support from family
and no other physical issues.
I want to know why she
tried to kill herself.
Well, she's 85. She's ill.
There's a possibility
she may just be ready.
She'll need dialysis in the next
year, but she's far from terminal.
We're all terminal.
It's just a case of when
we figure that out.
We owe it to her to be sure.
You know, we do have a policy.
If a case bumps against
a doctor's belief
system, -he's allowed to hand it off.
This has nothing to do
with my belief system.
It's about making sure that I'm
everything that I can for Mrs. Joseph.
And for her daughter, who isn't
ready to lose her mother.
Okay, see what psych has to say.
Thank you.
The kid's been in the room for
three hours. I need the bed.
Give him a little longer.
I think you should put him out
of his misery and drain it.
Well, thanks for your opinion.
I'll let you know what I decide.
Is this your priapism? The
kid's afraid of a needle?
I think he's more afraid to
tell his mom he's having sex.
Well, you know we do have a policy.
If a case bumps against a
doctor's belief system,
he is allowed to hand it off.
I'm just trying to be his ally.
A minor can make a consent for himself,
as long as you're confident
that he understands the
weight of the decision.
Either way, Claire's right.
What goes up must come down.
Glad I'm not a teenager these days.
Glad I never had to raise any.
Speaking of, how's yours?
Barely talking to me, as usual.
Oh. Guess it's your move then.
I haven't noticed you fasting.
It isn't Ramadan.
That's a different Eid.
Oh... Hey, mind if I ask you a question?
Mm-hmm.
So there's Christmas
and Easter Christians,
there's Sunday Christians, there's
every day, all day Christians.
Is it kind the same thing with Muslims?
- It's complicated.
- But you pray every day?
Some days, I pray five times a day.
And some days, I don't pray at all.
I thought you weren't working today.
Weren't you supposed to go home?
Yeah. I picked up a shift.
Melissa thinks it's hard on the girls
when I'm in and out so quickly.
You know, we decided
I should only go back when I
can stay for a longer time.
That can't be easy.
It's for the best.
I can focus on my work.
Will?
Will! Hey! You're awake!
Oh, thank God!
About earlier I... I don't...
Don't say anything.
Just don't go.
I won't.
Will. I love you.
Will?
Will, hey! Help!
Help, help, help!
I need help in here!
Pressure's tanking. What happened?
Is he seizing?
He was awake for one
second then he wasn't.
Ma'am, I need you to step back.
Looks more like decorticate posturing.
Intracranial hemorrhaging?
We checked his whole body, there
was no sign of head trauma.
We need to intubate, get him to CT.
Repeat his blood work.
- Prep 30 etomidate, 100 sux.
- Got it.
His INR levels were elevated but
within range for a trauma
patient with coagulopathy.
What are you thinking, blood thinners?
Well, if he's on them, he's gonna bleed.
Even the slightest bump to his
head could trigger a hemorrhage.
Lucy, you said that Will wasn't
taking any medication. Are you sure?
But if there's any chance he
was taking blood thinners,
we need to know now.
We... We haven't been
together for five months.
I left him.
I'm not going to admit
Lena Joseph to psychiatry.
She wants to die, that
means she's depressed.
Not in the way I choose
to treat clinically.
Is this about her age?
Would you say the same
thing if she was 20?
Maybe not. But that's my point.
You see, most of what we do here
is artificially prolonging life.
Resuscitation,
catheterization, surgery...
She's wrestling with this because
she's in her 80s and ill.
It would be a mistake to apply
a black and white stance to
a more nuanced situation.
I don't consider wanting to
help her taking a stance,
I consider it my responsibility, doctor.
Wanting to control the way
we go out isn't uncommon.
Look, as her primary physician,
you can keep her in a
72-hour psych hold,
but if it was just up to me?
I'd cut her loose as soon as
she's physically ready to go.
Well, then I'm glad it isn't up to you.
You're the doctor from Syria? Yeah?
I treat a lot of patients
who come from war zones.
We just met, so this is not a judgment,
but if you ever need to talk to someone,
feel free to reach out.
Don't you have a fancy coffee
machine in your office?
Well, I'm a man of the people, Claire.
Of course, and by that you
mean another egomaniac
doctor who knows everything?
Well, yeah.
But if you're still holding a
grudge against Dr. Hunter,
- then you shouldn't because he's...
- A good guy?
Do you want me to talk to him?
Uh, no. No, it wasn't a big deal.
And you know I can fight my own battles.
Of that, I am well aware.
Is that it? You just came to tell me
all the different ways in
which I disappoint you?
And that I changed my mind.
About Theo?
About dinner.
You asked me the other day.
Tonight?
Tomorrow. And I'm buying.
I just got an offer on the house.
You're selling your mother's house?
You love that house.
Well, I've been letting go
of a few things lately.
Well, I'll book us a table.
Somewhere expensive.
Right now, we're balancing
two opposing problems.
Will's abdominal injury from the bullet,
and the brain bleed, which is what
caused him to lose consciousness.
Can you fix them?
Individually, yes.
But they both require
equally emergent surgeries.
There are risks either way,
but the surgeons will want you
to weigh in on who goes first.
They want me to decide?
Well, even if you're separated,
while legally married, you're
still his next of kin.
But you said he was stable.
Blood thinners make your
blood less likely to clot.
Which makes you more susceptible
to internal bleeds.
- There are precautions, but...
- But you didn't know.
Will's had a tough year.
His father had all these
heart problems and um...
I cheated on him.
We met up today, and he...
said he forgave me.
That he still loved me.
But I didn't say it back.
Not until just now,
when I saw him, and he
needed to hear me say it.
But it wasn't true.
- You can do this.
- No.
I'm the one that keeps on hurting him.
How can I be the one making
decisions about his life?
You decide.
No. I can walk you through
the options, but I can't...
Please.
We'll do this together.
I'm sorry. I can't.
Hey. Are you okay?
You're sweating.
He could die, and she could just...
How could she just walk away?
Listen. It's not our job to
make her a stronger person.
Alright? Did you find out why her
husband's on blood thinners?
She didn't know.
I think I might, though.
And deep breath in.
What happens now? Are you
gonna let me go home?
Not until I'm sure you're ready.
Until you're sure I won't
do it again, you mean.
Your daughter is very
concerned about you.
You think I'm selfish.
If I was your mother,
you'd be upset too.
I watched the sacrifices Erin made
to be with her father
through his illness.
It just seemed like...
if I was ready anyway, why
wouldn't I spare her that?
In my experience, people don't
always want to be spared.
Tell me the OR's ready for him.
Well, neurosurgery and Trauma
are both saying their
needs are priority. So...
And his wife walked away.
Then I make the call.
Between two terrible options.
Unless there's a third that
I'm not smart enough to see.
Well, actually there is.
Will's father had a heart attack.
- So you did get a history?
- No, it was more like a confession.
But turns out Will has a family
history of heart problems,
which may be why he's on blood thinners.
His INR is two,
so he's more likely to be on Coumadin
than any of the newer anti-coags.
And if we dose him with vitamin K
and a prothrombin complex concentrate,
then we can reverse his
propensity to bleed.
That could buy time.
Neuro could go in, start the
craniotomy, relieve the clot,
then Trauma can take over and
fix the intra-abdo bleed.
Get the surgeons talking
to each other. Go.
Oh, uh... Sorry. I'm sorry.
Are you okay?
- Hey.
You looking for someone?
My little sister.
She's supposed to be
here doing her homework.
Homework on a Saturday?
Girl after my own heart.
Bathroom, maybe?
Yeah, probably.
Seriously, I don't know how you do it.
This job, and taking
care of your sister...
I mean, I barely remember
to eat until four.
I wouldn't exactly call that a meal.
Did I see you checking your pulse?
It's just an intense day.
Want me to help you look for her?
Yeah, oh...
Um... it seems Arnold already found her.
Excellent.
This young lady says
she's related to you?
She's supposed to be related
to me in the cafeteria.
Thank you.
You promised me you wouldn't move.
I know.
This isn't a playground, Amira.
This is my job.
I know.
What's wrong?
I just wanted to remember how it felt.
When Mama and Baba
would take me to work.
It's Eid.
We're all supposed to be together.
You never talk about them. I'm
afraid I'm going to forget.
Is this the famous sister?
Amira. This is my boss, Dr. Bishop.
Very nice to meet you.
She was just headed back to the
cafeteria to finish her homework.
Oh, fantastic. So was I.
Not to do homework, obviously.
I was gonna use my privileges
to see if I could swing
some free snacks.
Interested?
Come on. I guess your
brother has to work.
She's been awake since this
started, but feeling off.
I'm cycling her BP.
She said she felt light-headed,
then that monitor started beeping.
Page cardiology. Wide
complex tachycardia.
Let's start an Amiodarone infusion.
- Okay.
What you are experiencing is
called ventricular tachycardia.
It's an irregular heartbeat
likely brought on by electrolyte
abnormalities from not eating,
coupled with our
interventions earlier today.
Can you stop it?
She'll need an angiogram
and we'll run medications.
If she becomes unstable,
then we'll shock her heart
to restore a normal rhythm.
No.
I thought you wanted to come home.
No honey, you wanted me to.
And I was willing to do it for you.
But if Dr. Hamed is saying
this could be it...
What would happen to her then?
Without medications or an intervention
to reset her heart rhythm,
you'll... you'll likely go
into cardiac arrest and die.
No.
Please, honey.
This is what I want.
You need to save her.
Is there where *** come?
The trauma bay, yes.
That's where we do what's
called extreme measures
to try to save people's lives.
Does my brother do that?
Well, I'll deny it if
you tell him I said so,
but he's practically an expert.
Our parents were doctors.
They had a hospital in Syria before...
before we came here.
I never brought my son to the hospital.
Maybe I should have.
Definitely you should have.
Okay.
I can let you consent to
the procedure on your own,
but if you don't want
talk to your parents,
you need to talk to me first.
That girl you were going to meet...
she your girlfriend?
What, like, you mean going steady?
She's a girl I know from school.
Were you planning on using protection?
She said she's on the pill.
- Not good enough.
- Alright, okay?
I'll use a condom.
What about the pill you took?
Wanna explain to me why you did that?
I just wanted to last.
My friends say they can
go for 30 minutes.
Your friends are lying.
Ten minutes is normal, no matter
what the internet tells you.
More importantly, if you have to
take a pill to impress a girl,
she's not the right girl.
You're telling me every girl you've
been with was the right one?
I am.
Because there's only been one,
and I'm still married to her.
One girl? This whole time?=
Thirteen years and counting.
And you're trying to teach me about sex?
How do you even know anything?
Well, I know...
that decisions have consequences.
You're going to want
to take a deep breath.
She's still in v-tach. Cardioversion
is the only other option.
She requested a DNR and you
want to reset her heart?
There's still a case for a psych hold,
which would grant her
daughter power of attorney,
so we can avoid the DNR.
Well, Lena Joseph is your
patient, not her daughter.
It's her wishes you'd be dismissing.
No, it's her I'd be giving up on.
You're a man of instinct.
I know you can make hard
choices and save lives.
That's not what you've
been asked to do here.
Could be a couple of hours...
no more than a day.
I thought we were on the same side.
We are.
Hers.
I know it's hard, but we have to
respect your mother's wishes.
If I just had more time,
I could make her see I
don't care if it's hard.
I just don't wanna lose her.
Now there's nothing I can do.
But there is something you can do.
You can take the chance to say goodbye.
My parents...
My parents both died suddenly.
Long before I was ready to let them go.
This may not be the way that
you want to say goodbye,
but this time that you
have with her is a gift,
if you choose to see it that way.
Hey
I shouldn't have left. It
was the wrong thing to do.
Things just got so messed up, I...
Is he... is he okay?
He's in surgery.
We were able to reverse the
effects of the blood thinners
and stabilize him for both operations.
So he's going to make it?
It's too soon to tell,
but the surgeons felt that
the risk was acceptable,
given the alternative.
When he wakes up, and when he's ready...
I'm going to tell him
that he deserves to be
with someone who loves him back.
Code Blue, OR 2. Code Blue, OR 2.
Wait over here.
As your rhythm continues to deteriorate,
you may feel the need for
more pain management.
Let us know if that's the case.
Honey.
I know this isn't easy for you.
We'll be back to check you
have everything that you need.
There is one thing.
My goulash recipe.
I need to pass it on.
You always said you'd
take that to your grave.
And here we are.
We could use a pen and paper.
Mom, none of this is rational, you know?
Some things just aren't.
Hey.
What are you doing right now?
- Nothing, why?
- I need a favour
We did everything we could.
But in spite of our best effort...
Will didn't survive his surgery.
Will's dead?
He fought really hard, Lucy.
But in the end, both
injuries were just...
they were too much for him to handle.
You said he was going to be okay!
How... How am I supposed to live
with things ending this way?
I trusted you, and you didn't save him!
Maybe if we'd looked twice
at his elevated INR...
Don't do that. Alright?
You did everything medically
possible to help that man.
You even tried saving his marriage.
She was upset. Her husband just died.
You can't control the
way she reacts to that.
Dr. Curtis isn't wrong.
It was out of our control.
That's the job.
We move on and focus on
the things we can fix.
Oh, God!
- Uh...
- Charlie, don't move!
I'm sorry, sir. He
just got away from me.
- You okay, Charlie?
- Don't move, don't move.
- I'm good! I'm good!
- No, no, no!
Whoa, whoa! Okay! Not so good!
Welcome back, Charlie.
Try to stay with him this time, Lou.
Okay... Where does it hurt?
You know I'm not
embarrassed of you, right?
But you don't want anyone
knowing about us, though.
It's nobody's business.
Mm... So we can only be together when...
nobody's around?
You want me to tell everyone
you're my boyfriend?
Fine. He's my goddamn boyfriend.
You happy?
What? 'Cause you told Charlie?
No offence Charlie.
That's okay.
I mean, I... I got a
goddamn girlfriend too.
I can't find her though. She
got snakes in her veins.
- Snakes in her veins?
- Yeah.
- Just like me.
- Means an IV?
Is your girlfriend a patient here?
Is that who you've been looking for?
Obviously.
Any shortness of breath now?
No.
But I felt something earlier today.
Rhythm looks good now.
What were you doing at the time?
Managing the wife of a critical patient.
We lost him.
I've been living with
this long enough to know
that my symptoms can
sometimes be psychological
They can also be physiological.
- Yes.
- The only way for me to know
is to see you more regularly,
and get a fuller picture.
Every time I come here,
I feel like the...
Like the sick little
kid everyone worried
would never be strong enough.
That's why it's so important
to be on top of this.
So you don't have to be that kid again.
Jonah, I...
I wanted to see... how you are.
There's something I need to tell you.
Do young people even check
their voicemails these days?
I'll send yoa text.
It's your father.
Am I doing it right now?
Uh, yeah.
Do you think it's ready?
Uh, no keep stirring.
Almost.
- Eid Mubarak!
- Lamb! Bash!
Dr. Hunter brought lamb!
But every butcher I called was sold out!
Us country boys have our connections.
It's called Costco. Haha.
It's Halal, I swear.
Shukraan, Theo. Come on in.
You are saying that you haven't
seen either one of them?
I always fall asleep.
If I had to pick one...
An impossible question.
The first is the perfect horror film.
The second is the ultimate action movie.
He made me watch them both,
honestly I thought they
were the same movie.
Bashir...
Brother, sometimes I don't
know how we are friends.
Theo, are you not enjoying the food?
- Excuse me.
- Take some more!
When you were three years old,
you'd wake up at dawn every morning.
Mama and Baba were
working and exhausted,
but one of them would always get
up early and play with you,
or take you for a walk.
They did?
When you finally started sleeping in,
I would sometimes catch
them up early, just...
sitting beside you.
Watching you.
Mama once told me that...
no matter how tired she was,
it was always her favourite
way to greet the morning.
- Synced and corrected by martythecrazy -
- www.addic7ed.com -