If you leave against medical advice,
I need you to sign something
- that says you understand the risks.
- No problem.
If you want to apply,
you'd have my recommendation.
Theo, you didn't say yes, did you?
I treat a lot of patients
who come from war zones.
- (GUNFIRE)
- I hesitated.
I think we both know
it was more than that.
(DR. MITCHELL): As physicians, we're
trained never to show weakness.
This, despite the long hours...
patients' lives in our hands,
their deaths on our minds.
We're taught to suck it up,
and roll on to the next.
But that's unrealistic.
The weight of the job gets to us all.
Not just doctors who've
come from war zones.
Have you been to counseling before?
- No.
- Okay.
Then let's start with why you're here.
I was told I had to be here.
You don't think you should be?
That's what we're here
to figure out.
The day that building
down the street exploded,
I understand you were affected?
Lost focus during a medical procedure?
(SIRENS WAILING)
It was an intense day.
I'm sure it was.
Was it the first time something
like that has happened, or...
have you lost focus before?
Maybe even lost time?
It's been a few weeks since
you were referred to see me.
I'm curious, why come now?
(MEDICAL MACHINE BEEPING)
(BASHIR): Patient's stab wound is
causing intensive internal bleeding.
BP's crashing! Sats are 70% and falling.
She's gonna need blood.
Activate massive transfusion protocol.
On it. Putting red cells
through the rapid infuser.
With an aortic bleed this severe,
we need to put in a REBOA?
Let's X-ray first,
rule out thoracic aortic injury.
Can I get a plate, please?!
One, two, three! One, two, three!
(MACHINES BEEPING RAPIDLY)
Exposing.
I need a catheter,
14 gauge needle,
introducer, REBOA kit, and 30 cc's
of saline and contrast, stat.
X-ray's up.
- Status?
- Zone one, no widened mediastinum.
Patient is 35 years old,
penetrating wound to the abdomen,
hypovolemic, and percutaneous
cannulation is possible
Good. Dr. Curtis, take point.
Sir, I've done a REBOA before.
Then you're not missing out,
are you? Dr. Curtis?
Uh... Start an art line?
- Art line's in.
- Alright.
Puncturing femoral artery.
Inserting guide wire.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC)
Inserting introducer sheath.
- (MACHINES BEEPING RAPIDLY)
- Alright...
- Inserting REBOA.
- Mm-hmm.
Then you inflate the
balloon inside the artery,
and it stops the bleeding.
Alright, I think I'm there.
Inflating now.
- I think we got it.
- (CLAIRE): Pressure's coming up
BP's stabilizing, 90 over 60.
Alright good, let's get her to OR.
I'm gonna need that shiv
for evidence.
They'll take it out it in the OR, sir.
You'll just have to wait.
I had a patient recently.
A prisoner.
She got me thinking.
(THEME MUSIC)
- Synced and corrected by martythecrazy -
- www.addic7ed.com -
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
'Kay. Who wants pancakes?
- Me!
- Me! Me!
Okay, Abby, go get the bowls.
Grace, you get the milk and the eggs.
Okay? Get going!
And you, you get the day off.
Did you want to take
Grace swimming?
She's been asking for some
one-on-one before you leave.
Sure. You know, actually I...
was kind of hoping for
some one-on-one with you.
- Hmm.
- Uh...
You know, I feel like we haven't
really had a chance to talk.
(PHONE RINGING)
(THEO SIGHS)
Hunter residence.
Oh. Hi, Caitlin.
Okay, how long has he had the fever?
Alright, well I'll swing
by and take a look. Okay?
Alright, bye.
I forgot I promised your dad I'd
take his Saturday house calls.
Good for him to practice
letting go,
since you're taking over soon.
Right. Uh, Mel...
Don't worry, we'll save you
some pancakes!
(UNCOMFORTABLE CHUCKLE)
(CARS HONKING, TRAFFIC PASSING)
(CLAIRE): Okay, this might sting a bit.
What do we have here?
Uh, this is Chris and Camille,
who were on a pretty ambitious
bike ride and had a wee mishap.
My fault. I got a cramp
and swerved right into Cam.
- We rode all the way from Montreal.
- Mmm.
We're making a pilgrimage
to Niagara Falls.
I've always wanted to see it.
On bikes? May I ask why?
Ask Cam. I wanted to drive.
I used to go as a kid,
and Chris never did.
It's the cheesiest place on Earth,
and I do love that kind of thing,
so I told him the deal was we ride,
and stop at every tourist
attraction along the way.
We saw the giant apple on the 401,
a steam engine museum in Kingston...
- Until today when he took us both down.
- (CHRIS CHUCKLES)
Well, you're gonna need
stitches...
Ah...
Your range of motion is okay.
Let's ice it, and see when
the swelling goes down.
Cam fell harder than I did.
She cracked her helmet.
(CLAIRE): You didn't mention that.
I-I feel fine.
Well, you can't be too careful
when it comes to a head injury.
Take a seat, please.
We'll do a CT just in case.
Stay. Stitch. I'll call
radiology and find them a room.
(WOMAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY OVER PA)
Stomach cramps, broken toe,
and some kind of rash.
Take your pick.
Dr. Leblanc,
my overnight resident has
to miss today and tomorrow.
Can you cover ten to six?
Is there someone else
that can do it?
What? I'm taking less doubles,
is that so hard to believe?
- Yeah.
- You were my first ask.
But I'm sure I can cover.
But I will take all those
patients. Thank you very much.
Let me know if you can't fill it.
Is she back down here
for good, now?
I guess. She was only up
in Internal for, like, a week.
You didn't ask her?
Why would I? It's personal.
- Hello again, Mister...?
- CO Roberts.
Dr. Hamed. I'd like
to update Ms. Spencer.
- The nurses tell me she's awake.
- Yeah, come on.
Someone's popular.
Huh. Doctors don't count.
I'd like to do a quick
physical exam, Ms. Spencer.
I think he wants you
to leave, Marty.
- Behave.
- Oh, come on, I'm reformed!
(SCOFFS)
He seems nice.
Mm...
How are you feeling?
Like I lost the fight.
I'd have to see your opponent
to know for sure.
I guess if I don't make
it, we'll know she won.
Well, let's not call it
just yet. Deep breath.
(SLOW INHALE)
(PAINED EXHALE)
The wound to your abdomen
sliced an artery
which we sealed in the trauma
bay and repaired in OR.
You lost a significant amount of
blood, but you're stable now.
Feels like I was hit by a truck.
Pain at this point is normal.
My vision's blurry and there's, like,
pins and needles in my arms.
Is that normal too?
Give me your hands.
Just this one.
Okay, good.
Those symptoms are common
lingering effects of anesthesia.
We'll keep an eye on it to
make sure nothing's wrong,
and hopefully you'll be in
good shape before you go home.
Go back.
I've been in lock-up
my entire adult life.
It is home.
A nurse will be here to give
you something for the pain.
In the meantime, if there's
anything you need,
you let us know.
Hey, um, actually yeah. Do...
Do you think maybe someone could
um, get in touch with my mother?
We're not exactly on the
best of terms, but...
maybe if you tell her I was on
death's door and all that...
- Are you allowed visitors?
- If she's willing to come.
I think Marty will let her in.
(JUNE LAUGHING)
Dr. Curtis, can I borrow you
for something?
- You need a surgical consult?
- Regular exam.
It's pediatrics.
The on-call pediatrician
is swamped today.
Good news is the boy's vomiting
seems to have stopped.
Fantastic.
Hi, Glenn, I am Dr. Curtis.
I hear you've been throwing up
at the Royal Ontario
Museum this morning?
How long have you been
feeling sick... buddy?
Okay, uh...
It says here you refused
to call your parents?
Is there a reason for that?
My mom's in New York for meetings.
She's gone a lot.
Got it. What about Dad?
'Kay. Uh, why don't you lie down for me?
Does that hurt?
Did you eat anything at the museum?
No? So you were just...
hanging out by the bat cave
and started vomiting?
The fossils.
- What?
- I like the fossils, not the bats.
Okay.
Do you remember about what
time you started feeling sick?
Listen, you gotta give
me something, alright?
Oh!
Nurse!
(WOMAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY
OVER PA SYSTEM)
(WOMAN COUGHING)
(COUGHING)
Hi. Jessica Brown. Firefighter.
Oh yeah, we've met before.
Your O2 sats were 88%,
your lung capacity was low,
but you didn't want to stay
for more pulmonary tests.
Good memory. (COUGHING)
You're not coming from a fire.
Captain said if I'm out of
breath on the treadmill,
I'm not cleared for active duty.
It's been getting worse for days,
and he made me come
and get checked.
Okay. Breathe in.
- (JESSICA BREATHES DEEPLY)
- Cough for me, please.
(COUGHING)
(SOFT MUSIC)
Any other symptoms?
A fever on and off.
And I've been pretty tired lately.
Okay well, I'd like to run full
labs and get you a new chest X-ray,
and consult with a
respirologist this time
if you're open to it.
Guess I knew that was coming.
(INHALES) Yeah, okay.
- I'll be right back.
- (JESSICA COUGHING)
Do you know what kind
of crime she committed?
Murder, I think.
At least that's what the paramedic
heard from the prison transport crew.
Wow. Guess it's gotta be pretty
brutal to land you in max security.
Apparently she was only
18 years old.
- Eighteen?
- Hey.
We should respect her privacy. Hmm?
(BEEPING)
She can't feel her arms or legs.
Nicole. Can you
wiggle your fingers for me?
I can't.
Is it still the anesthetic?
That's unlikely. Are you on
any other medication?
No, nothing.
Narcotics? Would I find
anything in your system?
- Jesus, you didn't.
- No, I didn't.
But I did get in a fight with Gina.
More fights? When was this?
Yesterday.
Gina stabbed me with a needle.
(ROBERTS SIGHS) - Where?
If someone has it out for you,
you need to come to me!
I started it, okay?
- Nicole, where were you stabbed?
- In my left thigh.
(ROBERTS): What are you doing, Nic?
This is infected. Any idea
what was in that needle?
Heroin at some point, probably.
This is from an infection?
Possibly. We'll aspirate
and run a tox screen to confirm.
- Can you stop it?
- Depends on what we're dealing with.
(SIGHS)
You're almost getting out.
What are you thinking?
I get it. You're pissed.
You made your point, okay?
Are you trying to blow
your release?
Because that's what
you're doing here, Nic.
I'll be right back.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC)
So I figured, you know,
maybe this is a flu
or, like, food poisoning, but
Glenn's anemic and his BP is high.
Maybe it's a dietary issue
or nutritional deficiency.
I don't know. Viv's trying
to track down his mom.
Has he told you anything helpful?
He's not exactly a big talker.
Then get him to open up.
Of course, get him to open up...
Okay, Glenn, I'm gonna
need some answers, buddy.
Glenn?
Glenn.
Look, the blood tests are telling me
that you aren't getting
enough iron. Okay?
- Does your mom cook vegetarian?
- No.
Are you eating enough
red meat at home?
- Yes.
- Does your head hurt?
Is anything else that is off, or weird?
I am weird, okay?!
(SCOFFS) I don't think you're weird.
Do you sometimes have
a hard time hearing?
How's your concentration?
(MUMBLING): I don't know.
Okay. You're gonna have
to show me your teeth.
Come on.
Like this. There we go.
Okay. This is really important. Alright?
Do you live in an old house?
The paint on the walls, is it
peeling or anything like that?
(TENSE MUSIC)
It's getting worse.
I... I can't feel my arms,
and it's harder to breathe.
The tox screen confirmed you have
what's called wound botulism,
from whatever bacteria
was in that needle.
- Botulism?
- That's why she can't move?
Botulism can cause double-vision
and paralysis of voluntary muscles
You can give her antibiotics
With an infection this serious,
we use a targeted antitoxin.
It's being prepared right now.
- What?
- (ROBERTS): What?
The medication is time-sensitive.
Without knowing how far the
infection has progressed,
we can't be sure it will work
before paralysis takes a hold
of your major body functions,
like your heart and lungs.
Which means...
she stops breathing?
She... dies?
Guess I might lose
that fight after all.
We're going to do everything we can
to make sure that doesn't happen.
Hey. Hey.
You are not losing this fight.
You got that, Nic?
(TENSE MUSIC)
Dr. Hamed. Dr. Hamed!
- Yes, sir?
- Hey.
When are we gonna know if this drug
you're giving her is gonna work?
Once we start the infusion, we keep
an eye out for negative reactions.
After that, it's wait and see.
And there's nothing else
we can do in the meantime?
No, sorry.
Nicole asked me to contact her mother.
Our social worker is
trying to reach her.
Thirteen years she's been in max.
Mother never showed, not once.
You said earlier
that she was getting out.
Her release is soon?
Statutory after two thirds
of her haul.
Never slipped once, until now.
Nic was a kid when she came in.
My own daughter was
just born at the time.
Anyway, she worked hard to change.
But bringing this trouble on herself?
You see that when they don't wanna go.
When they're scared to.
(SOFT MUSIC)
Alright, thanks.
You're tired because your body's
not getting enough oxygen.
Unfortunately, this tissue...
here in your right lung, is dead.
And the dead tissue caused an
infection that's led to sepsis.
Can I fight that off?
The infection, yes.
But the underlying cause...
I'm sorry, Jessica.
There were indicators before,
but now it's confirmed.
You have COPD.
Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease.
It's a progressive disease, and
we are seeing signs of emphysema.
(JESSICA SIGHS)
Go on, say it.
If I'd seen a specialist before...
No. No.
There's no guarantees it
would have changed anything.
But it is stage three,
which means you have
to take it seriously.
I'm only 32.
I have my whole career ahead of me.
I'll start you
on IV antibiotics right now,
to deal with the infection,
and I'm gonna set you
up a surgical consult
to see what the options are beyond that.
Hey. What do you have?
Thirteen-year-old boy
with severe lead toxicity.
You ever treated that?
No, but normally it's chelation
therapy to flush it out.
You'll need to source out
the cause of the exposure
to make sure it's not ongoing, though.
- Do you have time for a consult?
- What do you have?
COPD with progressive emphysema.
She's a candidate for bullectomy,
which could improve her
breathing significantly.
So if you already know that,
what do you need me for?
I just thought that if you do
the consult,
aren't you more likely to
assist with the procedure?
I can ask someone else if you're busy.
No, I'm good. (CHUCKLES)
Thank you.
(NICOLE WHEEZING SLOWLY)
It's not working.
You're not responding to
treatment as well as we'd hoped.
Did you get in touch
with my mother?
Uh... Our social worker
spoke with her, but...
She's not coming.
(WHEEZING)
I'm sorry, Nicole.
(SOFT MUSIC)
(DR. MITCHELL): That's heartbreaking.
She shut down.
She wouldn't discuss any other
treatment options with me after that.
Why do you think that was?
With her prison term
coming to an end...
I think that she thought if
her mother would forgive her,
that she would deserve to get out.
Same reason
she was starting fights.
Because your patient didn't
think she deserved her release.
And knowing that her mother
wouldn't come,
even when she was so sick,
made her give up on life.
Alright, so we finally got
ahold of your mother.
She's gonna take an early flight back.
Says she has no idea what
could be causing this.
But if you do, you should tell me.
You won't get in trouble.
Okay, what if I tell you there's
a twenty in it for you?
(THEO): Wait. You, you bribed him?
(JUNE): I tried, it didn't work.
(SCOFFS) So... you're
saying he was thirteen?
Chelation therapy's not gonna
be easy for a kid his age,
but given how extensive his lead
poisoning is, he may need it.
Okay, so then
why are you calling me?
Because he won't talk to me.
You... you called me to ask
how to talk to your patient?
Well, I mean, normally
I deal with adults, okay?
I really need help.
Well, look... (GIRL): Dad!
You have to find a way to make
it seem like you're not trying.
You know? They usually wanna talk.
They just need to do
it on their own terms.
But look, I gotta go, June.
So good luck, okay?
Bye. Hey!
Camille Beaudry's CT is clear.
So they will be able to carry
on their cycling trip.
Oh, God.
There's not enough money in the world
to make me wanna ride a bike
down a highway days on end.
Oh, come on, it's romantic.
Spandex and semi-trucks?
No. Not my idea of romance.
So you'd prefer Sonoma Valley?
Mm-mm. Burning Man.
No phones. No rules
No showers. (CLAIRE CHUCKLES)
You'd really want to be stuck
in the desert for three days?
And you'd rather be touring some
stuffy medical museum in Paris?
(BISHOP SIGHS) Latvia. Riga.
Nights on the Baltic.
Why didn't you ever do that
with Katherine?
Same reason you didn't
do Burning Man.
Lives burdened by glorious purpose.
(BAGS JOSTLING)
Mel, I've been trying to find the
right time to tell you something.
I just, I need you to keep an open mind.
That permanent position
I told you about...
I applied, and Bishop offered it to me.
Why didn't you tell me?
I tried, Mel.
You just, you got upset.
And you walked it back and you
never even brought it up again.
When do you have to give him an answer?
You already said yes.
Okay, and I-I...
I know that was stupid.
Alright, but babe...
I haven't been this excited
about something in a long time.
I thought you were excited
to come home
Of course I am.
I-I just...
I can see a future there too, Mel.
For all of us. It's not just the job.
It's the people the kids would meet.
The opportunities.
My job is here, my parents,
our whole lives are here!
You would...
You'd get a job in a second.
(SOFT MUSIC)
Hey look, I know.
I know that if you
just gave it a chance,
you'd love it.
(SCOFFS)
Mel... Say something.
What am I supposed to say?
You wait until five
minutes before you leave
to drop this on me, and I'm
supposed to what, get on board?
- Mel...
- No! Just...
You better leave. You'll
miss your flight.
(SOFT PIANO MUSIC)
I reviewed your imaging
with the surgical team.
We can perform a procedure
called a bullectomy.
Essentially, we're gonna remove the
diseased air sacs from your lung.
Take out part of my lung?
It'll help the surrounding
healthy tissue grow,
and it would make a big
difference on your breathing.
You're young enough, Jessica,
we really feel this will have a
positive effect on your disease,
it can help slow progression, and...
- (WHEEZING)
- Jessica?
- (JESSICA): What's happening
- (WHEEZING)
Her heart rate's 200.
I need a crash cart here!
Jessica, I need you to stay
with me, alright?
Everything's gonna be
okay, just stay with me.
Jessica, COPD can trigger
heart problems, and right now,
your heart's not
in a normal rhythm,
and we're gonna
need to address that.
Okay? - What do we have?
Jessica Brown,
newly diagnosed COPD,
and now regular narrow complex
tachycardia, looks like SVT.
Okay. A re-entrant
tachycardia. Recourse?
Block antegrade conduction
and try to break it.
Okay, good.
Prep 6 milligrams adenosine IV push
with 20 cc saline flush.
(MACHINES BEEPING RAPIDLY)
Okay, Jessica, I'm gonna
give you some medication
that's gonna pause your heart,
but don't worry, it's gonna
start back all by itself.
(WHEEZING) Pause my heart?
But won't that kill me?
No. No. It's a very
quick procedure.
But your heart will stop
beating for a few seconds.
It's like hitting the reset button
What if it... (COUGHING)
What if it doesn't restart?
It will. We have the defib
here just in case, but it will.
Heart rate's still 200.
Jessica.
You run into fires every day.
This is nothing compared to that.
Trust me.
Let's do it.
You're gonna feel
a discomfort in your chest,
and a warming sensation.
Are you ready?
(JESSICA WHEEZING)
(INTENSE MUSIC)
(CONTINUOUS BEEP)
(JUNE): Flatline.
Come on, come on, come on.
- (MACHINE BEEPS)
- Regular sinus rhythm.
Welcome back.
Good work, everyone.
You okay?
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
Sir?
My botulism patient isn't
responding to the antitoxin.
- Options?
- I want to try a newer drug.
A higher potency synthetic compound.
Which is still relatively untested,
and therefore comes with a higher risk.
- It's shown results.
- What does your patient say?
Not much. She's afraid,
- disengaged from her treatment.
- Mm.
People don't always want
the things they need. Huh?
Talk to her. Get her consent.
Glenn. How's it going?
So, uh... speaking of weird...
The kids thought I was weird too.
Yeah. I know, right?
I was like a foot taller than
everyone else, which I hated.
And I didn't like talking to people.
Things at home weren't great.
I felt pretty alone. You know?
You sure talk a lot now.
(LAUGHING)
Okay. Alright.
So look, as you get older,
the thing you realize
is that, you know, the weird
kids grow up to be...
the cool kids.
(SNORTING)
You wanna see something awesome?
(SOFT MUSIC)
Ready?
You said you liked fossils, right?
Eh? Cool, right?
I mean, he's not real,
but he's to scale.
We use him for teaching. The
residents call him Maurice.
Say hi.
Shake his hand.
Have you been eating these?
I like the way they taste.
- What are they?
- Fishing weights.
How long have you been doing this?
About a month.
I got them from my
grandfather's tackle box.
He used to take me fishing.
Before he died.
We used to talk about stuff.
I bet you miss him, huh?
I feel alone too.
No, you're not alone.
But Glenn, how many of
these have you eaten?
A lot.
I tried to stop, but I can't.
I didn't know they were made of lead.
It's okay.
It's cool. I can help you with this.
Can I stay here a bit longer?
Definitely. You should
chill with Maurice.
Hairline fracture of the patella.
- It'll take 4 to 6 weeks to heal.
- Ugh...
Can't you give me a steroid shot?
You can walk on it, but a long ride
is definitely out of the question.
I'm sorry, Cam
- What?
- I booked a tour company
to the falls on the New York side,
and they have something I've never seen.
A chicken who does math.
(CAM LAUGHING)
I'm serious. She counts out
little kernels of corn
with her little, little beak!
Well, only a madman
could turn down that offer.
Then I guess I'm not.
Listen to the doctor.
All he wants is your consent.
What's the point?
Isn't it shift change?
Don't you gotta punch out?
The infection isn't stopping.
It's going to reach
your respiratory system
What happens if she doesn't
take the new medication?
If things continue as they are,
she's going to stop breathing
- within the next 24 hours
- You hear that?
- He says you'll die.
- I don't care.
Don't say that. Don't do this.
- Doc, please, you gotta talk to her.
- He's right, Nicole.
You don't have to give up.
You don't deserve to die from this
(STRUGGLING TO BREATHE)
You don't know me.
You don't know what I deserve
(ROBERTS): But I do.
I killed someone, Marty.
I took an innocent man
away from his family, his two kids,
just for the cash in his till.
It was a different person who did that!
(NICOLE WHEEZING)
The law says you paid your debt.
Well, I don't!
He's dead.
Why do I get to live?
Just... just go, home.
Just leave.
(NICOLE CRYING)
(DOOR OPENING)
- Hey, I'm home!
- Hey.
- What are you doing?
- Homework.
We had an algebra test,
and I didn't finish.
Now my teacher says I have to do
these extra problems for Monday.
Algebra still gives me nightmares
I bet you finished
your tests on time.
Not always. And I went
to school in my first language.
Amira, you're doing great.
And whenever you feel like you're not...
You come find me.
(DOOR OPENING)
Hey.
Homework on a Saturday?
- How was work?
- Long.
How'd it go?
Mel wasn't thrilled about
the idea of us moving here.
Give her time.
She'll change her mind.
What will you do if she doesn't?
- Amira.
- (THEO): No, it's okay.
I don't know.
Sounds like we could use a pizza.
- Oh, yeah. I'm in.
- Me too.
(SIRENS WAILING, TRAFFIC PASSING)
(SOFT MUSIC)
Uh, Nicole Spencer? Where is she?
They moved her to ICU overnight.
She lost consciousness
(TENSE MUSIC)
Blood pressure's low.
O2 sats are still falling.
They upped the infusion
of antitoxin, but...
She's not responding.
She's going into respiratory failure
Do you want to intubate?
Dr. Hamed?
We're going to try
a synthetic adenovirus.
(TENSE MUSIC)
Glenn's mother agreed
to the chelation therapy.
That should flush out the
rest of the lead toxicity.
He'll just be here a few days.
Okay, well the X-ray
confirmed all the lead weights
have passed from his system.
The way he described it, it
sounded like a compulsive habit.
That could be Pica.
It's an eating disorder brought on
by anxiety and major stress events
Glenn's grandfather
just passed away.
They were close, and now it's
just him and his mom, so...
Yeah, it's never easy.
Well, she's committed to helping.
So I'll refer them to a psychologist
who's worked with teens before.
More talking?
The kid's gonna love that.
(CHUCKLES)
Well, looks like you made
a new friend.
You really like doing
this stuff every day?
Yeah. I really do.
You put her on the adenovirus.
She was unconscious
when I started the infusion.
I had no choice but to
make an informed decision.
- Meaning?
- Meaning, I'm trying to help her.
You said yourself that people don't
always want the things they need.
Wouldn't you have done the same?
Wasn't it three weeks ago
I asked you to go see Dr. Mitchell?
Have you gone?
I'm trying to help you, too.
(TENSE MUSIC)
As soon as my infection gets better
they said they'll get me up for surgery.
You'll be up and around
in no time.
No more fires, though.
(MAGS SIGHS) No.
Not if you want to slow the
progression of your disease,
no.
(SOFT PIANO MUSIC)
Fighting fires was...
was the thing I picked.
Not marriage,
not kids.
You're still young, Jessica.
You've got your whole life ahead of you.
Maybe.
But I cut everything else out.
Without my job...
I'm not sure I know who I am.
Dr. Leblanc,
I'm still looking for someone
to cover tonight 10 to 6.
You said to tell you if
I hadn't covered it?
Yeah, um...
I'm sorry, Dr. Atwater. I can't.
Okay.
Hi, Dr. Curtis.
- What?
- Nothing, you have other plans?
- No, why?
- Well, good.
Just, you know, don't make any.
- Hey.
- Mr. Roberts.
(SIGHS) Nic's on the new meds?
And her deterioration is holding.
She's still critical, but we're hopeful.
She did shoot that man,
but what she didn't mention
was the abusive boyfriend
who dragged her into it.
He's doing life for that,
and another crime that she
had nothing to do with.
Nic never had anyone who
to look out for her.
Her first year inside,
she was too scared to sleep.
So we sat up nights playing
Scrabble until she could.
(LIGHT PIANO MUSIC)
Give that to her when she wakes up?
I guess she did have
someone looking out for her.
- Theo!
- Hey, Joanie.
I heard from my shift supervisor
you put in for a ride along?
I'm starting here full-time.
And you need
your EMS field experience.
Yeah, all permanent staff
need to log 20 hours.
Okay, well, if you can do next
Thursday, we'll take you with us.
That's perfect. Great! Thank you.
See you then!
(DISTANT SIRENS WAILING)
(CARS HONKING)
- Hey.
- Hi.
New nurses schedule.
I've added a second
overnight to Saturday.
- Wanna take a look?
- Claire, uh...
If I... If I were to ask you to...
come to the Baltics
with me, would you?
I thought you were too
caught up here,
burdened with "glorious purpose"?
Well, it wouldn't kill me
to take a vacation.
Mm. Burning Man?
Well... (CHUCKLING)
Possibly. I know...
I know you wanted some time on your
own to figure things out, Claire.
I just wanted to let you know...
I'd follow you anywhere.
Even the middle of the desert
with the great unwashed.
(SOFT MUSIC)
(GIGGLING)
Well, why don't we start small?
Take the same day off?
Go from there?
(DISTANT SIRENS WAILING)
So, Singh's going to let me
scrub in on the bullectomy.
Wait, is that...
is that why we're here?
- No.
- Is that why we're hanging out?
Listen. Don't... don't make
a big deal out of this.
Mm-hmm.
Well, last time I had
a beer and pretzels,
I was with my sister. (CHEWING)
She was getting married the next
day, and panicking about it.
Oh, okay, so...
Overthinking runs really
strong in your family?
- (LAUGHING)
- Yeah. Yeah.
- You have a brother, right?
- Yeah, uh, Charlie.
We have a strong
text-based relationship.
My sister and I, we used to...
we used to talk every day.
- Every day?
- Mm-hmm.
Wow.
Well, since my residency started,
it's been more like every, uh...
every few weeks, I'd say.
She used to let me pretend
to defibrillate her.
(LAUGHING) What?!
- I know.
- Are you serious?
Poor kid.
So, I guess you were one
of the weird kids too, then, huh?
Mm-hmm. Definitely.
Hmm, nice.
Well, cheers to the weirdos.
- Cheers.
- (GLASSES CLINKING)
(SOFT MUSIC)
What happened?
You survived.
(SIGHS) I survived, or...
You saved me?
I made a judgment call
when your life was in danger.
Yours was a fight I refused to lose.
Hmm.
Marty bring these?
- You ever play?
- With my little sister,
when she was learning English,
it helped with her spelling.
(KNOCKING)
Hey. Good to see you up.
Good to be up.
You got time for a quick game, or what?
Yeah, I could carve out
a few minutes.
Okay, I'm gonna beat you, though.
Yeah, well, there's a first
for everything.
Good?
Why don't I let you pick first.
Your patient struggle
to forgive herself.
It affected you.
It made you finally come see me.
Many of my patients who come from war
zones live with survivor's guilt.
(SLOW EXHALE)
You asked me what I saw
that day that building
across the street exploded,
and I lost focus during
a medical procedure.
I saw my mother.
(HIGH-PITCHED RINGING)
(SOFT MUSIC)
She was dead.
There was a bombing in the
clinic that my parents built.
The clinic they ran since
I was a child, and...
I was too late to save her.
And you can't forgive
yourself for that.
Every time I see my little
sister, I'm reminded...
of what we lost.
Reminded that the one thing she needs
is the one thing I can
never give her back.
Our parents.
(SOFT MUSIC)
- Synced and corrected by martythecrazy -
- www.addic7ed.com -
What happened with Amira?
Was everything okay?
There was an incident
with another student.
I tried talking to her but I guess
I'm saying all the wrong things.
A BREAKDOWN AT HOME
I hate it here! You hate it here?
You're the only reason were here.
It gets harder.
A RELAPSE IN THE ER.
- Sir?
- Dr. Bishop?
AND ONLY TWO EPISODES LEFT
GET INTO AN ALL NEW TRANSPLANT