All I could hear was
your voice in my head.
Telling you what?
That I'm focusing on
all the wrong things.
You should have helped me
when you had the chance!
- I've never punched back.
- My claim for asylum was denied.
(ARABIC) The police came to my house.
They were asking about you
at the hospital as well
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(LIQUID POURING)
(AMIRA): Bash, come quick!
Cecil's dead!
- What happened?
- I don't know.
He was on his wheel all night.
My class is going to hate me!
We have a hamster?
Um, Amira had one just
for the night,
a loan from her class.
She said she asked you.
I was going to.
- Ah!
- Cecil!
We've got him back.
(THEO): He's pretty cute. (LAUGHS)
Can I get one?
Uh, maybe when we get
our own place?
- But I like it here.
- I know.
But Theo will be leaving before long.
He's moving back to Sudbury
when his fellowship ends.
I thought you liked it here too.
I do, but my life is there.
Do you want to go?
(PHONE CHIMING)
I don't know.
I need to go.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC)
Khaled.
_
Keep pressure on it.
Let's get you to the hospital.
_
It's been two months since that police
officer came by asking for you.
I haven't seen her since.
_
Your ribs might be broken.
Let me look.
(KHALED WHEEZING)
It's possible a section of
your rib cage has detached.
How do I fix that?
You get imaging,
you could need surgery.
If the sharp edges of your
ribs puncture an organ,
it's life-threatening.
So is being sent back to Libya.
There's got to be something
else you can do.
(THEME MUSIC)
- Synced and corrected by martythecrazy -
- www.addic7ed.com -
(CARS HONKING)
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
Shopping for anything
in particular?
(BASHIR): Um...
A needle driver, toothed forceps,
4.0 sutures, antiseptic
wipes, and gauze.
Okay, well,
it's a disaster in here.
So tell me where you are,
and I will bring it to you.
What's up?
I know we treat patients
without insurance,
but what about patients without ID?
We treat whoever walks
in that door and needs it.
So, if they don't have ID,
you get a billing address.
Beyond that, hm, well...
money's accounting's problem.
And the information
that goes in the system,
that's protected?
Protected from who?
The police?
Our system is completely closed.
Law enforcement has no access,
unless, of course, they have a warrant.
Do you want to tell me
what this is about?
Um, it's probably better
if I don't.
Thank you.
Dislocated knee in two needs an X-ray
and 5 milligrams of IV morphine.
Exam four is sleeping it off,
so page me when he wakes up or his
IV runs out, whatever comes first
Did the ELISA go out for Alyssa?
The Lyme disease test on the tick bite.
Oh, yeah. Um, yes.
I sent it to Public Health.
Okay. Confirm with a Western blot
and tell her they'll follow
up when her results come in.
Do you need me to take some?
Ah, you're juggling already
with five patients.
And you must be tired
from your night shift.
- I can ask someone else.
- It's fine, it's fine.
- Are you sure?
- Here, yeah.
- I need a word with Dr. Leblanc.
- Yes, thank you.
I've been meeting my targets on
every shift, like you asked.
Yes, you've been very efficient.
I've organized a locum
on diagnosing subjective illness
and I've just had a presenter drop.
I was thinking about your amnesia case
from a couple of months ago.
Are you saying I can present?
Well, only if you have the time.
Yeah. Absolutely.
Thank you. When?
Tomorrow morning.
I can make that work.
I'll send you some sample slides
so you can get your visuals together.
It's a good opportunity for you.
Not many second-year
residents get the chance.
Thank you.
(BASHIR): I wish you'd come in.
I would be your doctor. You
know you can trust me.
But what about everyone else?
They have no reason to keep my secret.
Once you're a patient, there's
a duty of confidentiality.
For the doctors and nurses.
What if they asked some
security guard or janitor?
None of them will have
any idea about who you are.
I live with roommates
because I can't sign a lease.
(DISTANT SIRENS)
I'm always looking over my shoulder.
As your doctor, I'm telling
you, you need treatment.
And as your friend, I'm telling
you it's going to be okay.
Alright, so give him
2 milligrams of lorazepam
and we'll take him upstairs in ten.
Rhoda? You with me?
Do you know that guy?
Because he seems to know you.
(JUNE SCOFFS)
Dr. Curtis?
You handle the lorazepam,
I'll handle him.
- Hi, June.
- Not here.
What are you doing here?
It's not like
I have your home number.
Yeah, but there's a reason
for that.
I know you don't want to see me.
But I've been making
changes, taking steps.
Twelve of them.
- June...
- I'm not interested.
I promised myself I wouldn't push,
I just want to give you my number.
A father has a right to hope
his daughter will call.
In case you change your mind.
You're likely going to need
a surgical procedure
called a chest wall stabilization.
It will anchor your broken ribs
so that they heal properly.
(SIGHS) - How long will that take?
One step at a time.
This is Claire, she's
the head nurse here.
I have brought you something
for the pain.
- Any allergies to medication?
- No.
Do you know if your tetanus
is up to date?
We'll do the tetanus as well.
Oh, okay.
Now, if the pain gets any worse,
don't hesitate to let
any one of us know.
Thank you.
I'll get back to you when we have
a time slot available for surgery, okay?
Until then, get some rest.
So I take it he's a friend?
And the reason you asked me
about the police before?
He's... He's not a criminal.
He's just, uh...
he's undocumented.
We will take good care of him.
Hey, Laura. I'm Dr. Leblanc.
You were in an accident?
Uh, yeah.
I think my wrist might be broken.
Okay. Let's see, over here...
This....
Okay... Let me know if this hurts.
- Mm.
- Yeah?
Okay, we'll do an X-ray, and
take care of those scrapes.
Look over here.
Okay, again. Is someone here with you?
Mm-mm.
Okay.
Do you want to tell me
how you hurt yourself?
I, uh, I told the nurse.
A woman on a bike crashed into me.
I was crossing the street too quickly
and, uh... I thought
maybe I hurt her, but, uh...
Uh, she said that she was fine.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC)
Is that man with you?
(LAURA BREATHING HEAVILY)
Laura, I'm here to help.
But I can only do that if you
tell me what's happening.
Uh...
That man is going to tell
you that he's my father.
But he is not my father.
Please, just don't let him near me.
Fifteen years old,
pulled from a swimming pool.
Head trauma during a dive.
Lifeguards did CPR, got him
breathing within 60 seconds,
but he hasn't regained consciousness.
Pulse ox 95. BP 130 over 90.
Heart rate's 90.
On three. One, two, three.
Keep him on the long board,
C collar, and re-breather,
monitor O2, CO2, he'll need a CT.
Come on, buddy.
Try and wake up for me.
Localize his pain.
Incomprehensible sounds.
No eye opening. GSC 8.
Trey lost control of his dive.
That never happens to him.
Caught a piece of the lower
board on his way down.
He just folded into the water,
he wasn't even moving.
- How high was that?
- Seven-and-a-half metres.
After they pulled him out,
his body was just limp.
No bony deformities.
That mean you think
he's paralyzed?
We can't know that yet, right?
We need to do imaging,
we'll know more when we do.
(FATHER): Is he gonna be alright?
She's right, it's too early to tell.
Is there somewhere quiet we
can take Mom and Dad to wait?
- Please follow me.
- I wanna stay with him.
- Let the doctor do his work.
- We'll update you as soon as we can.
Gotta go.
(MEDICAL MACHINES BEEPING)
You trying to outrun
your problems?
What?
What problems?
Sick patients, ungrateful bosses.
Nosy boyfriends. (CHUCKLES)
I can handle those problems.
Dinner later?
Yeah, uh, actually I was kinda
hoping you'd be up for a change.
Yeah. Tasha needs me to take Henry,
he's been dying to go to the arcade.
You interested?
Oh.
I wasn't sure you were
ready for the whole...
girlfriend-kid crossover.
I'm ready. If you are.
Okay, well I mean,
as long as you and Henry
are okay with getting your asses
kicked at Space Invaders, 'cause...
Henry will be fine.
I'm a pretty sore loser.
Gotta...
(WHISPERING)
Mr. Abdullah
came in this afternoon,
I think he's got chest trauma.
Yes, yes but he's presently in treatment
and not available to be interviewed.
I just need a few
moments of his time.
As soon as he's off
of his morphine,
- I can reach out to you.
- Okay.
- Give me your contact.
- Certainly.
- Here you are.
- Thank you.
Thank you.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC)
Was that about Khaled?
Yeah. He knew he was here,
he asked for him by name.
How could he know that?
He said he was involved in
an incident this morning.
- What kind of incident?
- Didn't say.
Look, I told him the
patient is being treated,
and it'll be a while before
he's able to be interviewed.
- And he accepted that?
- For now.
Look, I want to help your friend.
But you think we should comply.
I don't think we have
a lot of choice.
Not reporting someone, and actively
hiding them from the police
are two very different things.
We can't stand between them.
- And you're sure he's coming back?
- Definitely.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC)
(♪)
I'd like to make
the Kocher incision on this one.
Your father's quite the character.
(JUNE SCOFFS)
You met my father?
He had a surgical consultation
with me this morning.
He didn't tell you?
I must have missed him.
Hmm...
He told me that you put
yourself through school
even though he offered to pay.
I'm sure that wasn't easy.
What else did he say?
Only that he was proud of you,
that he always knew you'd
be a good surgeon.
But I guess you knew that already.
Kocher incision's all yours.
See you in there.
I can't protect you if you
don't tell me what happened.
I didn't do anything wrong.
I believe you, but I
need the whole story.
My boss was behind in paying us.
It wasn't the first time,
so I said something.
He didn't like that, and he shoved me.
He pushed you off the roof?
I lost my balance
You're the victim in this.
Why didn't you tell me?
I knew you would tell me not to go back.
- You're still planning on it?
- I need the money?
He could have killed you.
You need to tell the police.
And give them a reason
to send me home?
I can't take the risk.
No, you deserve better.
If there was something better,
don't you think I would have taken it?
We can't all be doctors.
I'm alone here, Bashir.
The one who's supposed to build a life,
make enough money to
send for my family...
_
(VIVIAN): Thank you, Mr. Bailey.
I could show you a picture, too.
But I don't understand why
I'm being asked to do this.
We just need to verify
your connection with Laura.
How is she?
Am I able to see her now?
Mr. Bailey, I can't give
you medical information
on Laura without her consent.
So you're saying
Am she didn't consent? ow?
Does she know I'm here?
Were you with her earlier today?
You don't think I did
anything to hurt her?
Mr. Bailey, if you know
what happened to Laura
it could help Dr. Leblanc
understand the bigger picture.
We meet every week for brunch.
I was asking about her
plans for next year,
and I don't know, something set her off.
Set her off how?
(SIGHS) She's always
been very independent.
She doesn't like me auditing her life.
Maybe I pushed too hard,
asked too many questions.
I went to the bathroom, when I
came back, she was outside,
and she was getting into a cab
and her leg was bleeding.
Please, I just want to
make sure she's okay.
You can wait here.
Do we involve the police?
She didn't accuse him of anything.
See if she can offer
some more context first.
Okay.
Trey?
- Thank God, baby.
- (THEO): Hi, Trey.
I'm Dr. Hunter. You're in
York Memorial Hospital.
Do you remember what happened to you?
(GROANS)
Yeah
Good. That's a good sign.
How are you feeling?
Like I fell off a diving board
and hit another diving board.
(CHUCKLES) He sure sounds like himself.
Well, Trey's imaging looks good.
He has a concussion,
but there's no indication
of any spinal injuries.
Trey, I'm gonna get you
to squeeze my fingers
as hard as you can, okay?
(MEDICAL MACHINES BEEPING)
Hey, good. Alright, okay. Now push.
Okay.
Let's take a look at your feet.
I'm gonna raise those toes
up to your nose, okay?
(TREY GROANS) Hard as you can.
Alright. Now push towards me.
You're pushing as hard as you can?
Yeah. I just can't move
them that much.
Does that mean paralysis?
Or could it just be soreness?
No
Wanna say something, Trey?
It was like this before I dived.
That's why I fell.
Wait, your legs stopped
working before you fell?
Now is this the first time something
like this has ever happened to you?
It's been on and off, but...
they just get weak, it's
never this bad, though.
Why didn't you say anything?
Mom, the qualifications
for Nationals...
You were with him
at practice all week.
You should've noticed.
Only because you finished work
late all week,
- and I had to pick up the slack.
- Guys, please.
Sounds like you're quite the
accomplished diver, Trey.
He's ranked third in Ontario
for under sixteens.
- He's worked so hard.
- That's impressive.
I'm gonna run a few tests,
and when you're feeling up to it,
I'll be back for a few more questions.
But in the meantime, your job
is to stay calm and rest.
And your job...
is to make sure he can do that.
(SOFT MUSIC)
(INDISTINCT BACKGROUND CHATTERING)
- Oh, I'm sorry, I'm just...
- Texting and walking?
No, worse.
I'm researching and walking.
I'm doing a presentation
for Bishop's locum.
I heard. Short notice.
How are your slides coming?
I'll be able to write them on the phone.
I'm thinking of 30.
That's actually on the low end.
- Really?
- Mmm.
Well, I've got
about seven started...
in my head. (CHUCKLES)
You could've said no, Mags.
I didn’t want to waste that opportunity.
Being unprepared would be worse.
I won't be.
(TENSE MUSIC)
Hey, Mags.
Dislocated knee in two
is still reducing.
And your cycling accident
is back from X-ray.
- Okay.
Sir?
Yes, Dr. Hamed.
I can finish doing your
stitches for you if you'd like.
A physician should never
stop doing sutures.
Keeps you sharp.
A nurse will be in to see
you shortly, alright?
I have a patient
with a flail chest
and I'm looking for nonsurgical options.
Another patient of yours in
Syria you're treating by proxy?
No. He's in hospital.
(EXHALES) Pulmonary contusion,
three fractured ribs...
This patient needs surgery,
which I know you know.
He would rather not stay
in hospital to receive it.
You two have
a personal connection?
Whatever history you
have is inconsequential.
Except our history is the only
reason he came through the door.
And the minute he did,
you stopped being his friend,
and became his doctor.
Find a way to make him stay.
Can you feel this?
Hmm. Is he still out there?
- He is.
- (LAURA SIGHING)
Laura, you gotta tell me
what's really going on.
- You won't believe me.
- Try me.
It's my job to listen to my patients.
My dad used to be...
different.
He's changed.
Did he do this to you?
- He did.
- Who?
Him! Uh...
- Dr. Hunter?
- No, he is not a real doctor.
Please, just don't...
don't let him in here.
(EXHALES)
Okay.
(LAURA BREATHING HEAVILY)
June, how long would it take
to get a chest wall
stabilization through OR.
Oh, yeah. Claire said
you might have one.
- Diagnosis is confirmed?
- Yes. Flail chest.
But he's stable.
Well, it shouldn't
take long if he's ready.
- Want me to set it up?
- Yes, please.
(INAUDIBLE CONVERSATION)
I hear you are looking for
Khaled Abdullah. I'm his doctor.
When can I speak to him?
He's waiting for surgery right
now, and can't speak until after.
I just need to ask him
a few questions, sir.
Which he is under
no obligation to answer.
And if he does consent to an interview,
he'll need a lawyer present.
- Okay, uh, Doctor...?
- Hamed.
Dr. Hamed. You're worried I'm going
to find out is undocumented?
I already know that, sir.
He cannot be detained
or deported while in hospital.
Okay, sir, you're not getting it.
I'm not interested in either.
Your patient's employer hires
undocumented immigrants
and exploits them.
Witnesses saw him push Mr.
Abdullah off that roof.
I need your patient to
confirm that story.
That's why I'm here.
How can Khaled be sure
that after he speaks to
you, you won't report him?
Because Mr. Abdullah
is the victim here, sir.
And I'm just trying to help.
I don't care where he's from,
or what his status is.
One way or the other, I am
gonna have to talk to him.
Before you said you
couldn't tell me anything,
and now you're allowed to?
Did Laura change her mind?
We have discretion if we believe
a patient isn't in a position
to care for themselves.
You're saying she isn't?
Laura is, um...
is exhibiting signs of
paranoid delusions.
She claims that you are not her father.
She doesn't know who I am?
Our staff psychiatrist
is speaking with her now,
and he's gonna want to
speak with you too.
Could it be schizophrenia?
Well, we can't...
I mean, we're not jumping to any
conclusions without more information.
But does... does Laura have a
history of mental illness?
Her mother was diagnosed with
schizophrenia when Laura was young.
It was an uphill battle for a few years.
I did everything I could,
she didn't come home.
I should have seen the signs.
Was Laura exhibiting
behavioural changes?
She's seemed tired,
she was losing weight.
Putting pressure on herself.
A lot of busy people don't take the
time to eat or sleep properly.
So you couldn't have known
anything based on that.
Well, I guess I could've
rationalized most of it...
until today, when she's talked
about dropping out of school,
agitated in a way I'd never
seen from her before.
Well, Laura is here now,
and we're gonna do everything
you can to help her.
What if you can't?
What if it ruins her life
like it did her mother?
You're going to help me get out of here.
Instead, you talked to the police?!
He says he's only here to help.
- And you believe him?
- I don't think we have a choice.
You mean I don't have a choice.
(THEO): Hi, Trey.
Feeling up to a quick exam?
It's easy, I promise.
Why don't you sit up for me?
Folks not around?
No, um...
They're probably off somewhere
finding new ways to hate each other.
(CHUCKLES)
I want you to look at the pen,
but don't move your head, okay?
Do you think my legs
will get better?
Because I don't know what I'm
gonna do if I can't walk anymore.
What I can tell you is we're
gonna do everything possible
to find out what's causing
this, and to treat it.
Can I get you to touch each finger
with your thumbs, like this?
Well,
must take a ton of training
to dive at such a high level.
Yeah, um...
Two hours before school,
then two hours after school.
And on the weekends. So, you know...
- pretty light.
- (CHUCKLES)
Well, you must really love it.
Mmm...
I guess there's not much time
for anything else though, huh?
I don't really
get to see my friends.
And I pretty much live in a Speedo.
(LAUGHS)
Why don't you swing your legs
over the side of the bed?
Okay.
Now just hang them
all the way over and relax.
(TREY EXHALES) Alright...
It's pretty good!
Your, uh.... your folks
know you feel that way?
My diving's kinda the only thing
that's keeping them together.
It's kinda stupid.
I'm almost killing myself
instead of just being
straightforward with my parents.
Ah, it's normal,
to not want to upset the
people you're closest to.
But that's a lot of pressure
to put on yourself, Trey.
Yeah, I know.
Hey, Rhoda, um...
did our possible MI in exam
three have his angiogram?
Yeah, he's up there now.
Okay can you page me when
the result are in, please?
- You got it.
- Thank you.
(SIGHS)
Dr. Mitchell?
Was she uh, was she cooperative?
She was extremely agitated,
and it's too soon to establish
if she can be discharged safely.
I've given her some haloperidol
which will hopefully calm her.
I was hoping I was wrong.
Does that mean a Form 1?
Hopefully we don't get there.
If she's lucky, this could
be an isolated incident.
Yeah, but family history makes
schizophrenia more likely, right?
It could be hereditary, yes,
but even with the history,
we need more information.
Well, we know she's
been having delusions,
she stopped taking care of herself,
she's talking about
dropping out oh school.
It's all classic symptoms.
So you're a fan of textbooks,
Dr. Leblanc?
You know, in cases like these,
diagnosis is long and slow,
and patience is crucial.
It's important not to rush.
The father's desperate for answers.
He's gonna want to talk to you.
Yes, of course. Let him know I'll be
down to see him as soon as I can.
Okay. What can I do to help?
(CHUCKLES)
Most emerg residents who
transfer a patient to psychiatry
can't wait to race back to first
trauma with a cardiac arrest.
Yeah. I like to see my patients through.
Hmm.
Well, it sounds like you've
gained the father's confidence.
Maybe check in with him again
until I can get there.
Would be good to know
what kind of support he's
able to provide at home,
- so we get the whole picture.
- Right.
(INDISTINCT VOICE ON PA SYSTEM)
Right...
Then you call the school
and deal with it!
I can't be everywhere all at once!
Not today.
Makayla, nobody's asking you to.
I just...
- You're asking me to!
- Hey, Theo!
Why do people bring their
personal drama to the hospital?
Take it outside.
(SIGHS) At least they're not doing
it in front of their kid this time.
Your patient?
Yeah. 15-year-old
with intermittent attacks
of lower extremity muscle weakness
and spontaneous paralysis.
Brisk reflexes, symmetrical.
Kid lost control of his legs,
missed a dive and almost died
instead of telling his parents he
didn't want to compete anymore.
- It's a tricky differential.
- I had a patient with similar symptoms.
Turned out to be Transverse Myelitis.
I thought it might be that too
but the clinical course
has been intermittent,
which makes it unlikely.
But I ordered an MRI..
Thyroid disease?
(SIGHS) THS and T4 were normal.
Myasthenia Gravis?
He'd have extra-ocular muscle
weakness, bulbar symptoms.
You try telling the kid to nut up
and tell his parents how he feels?
I did recommend that treatment.
Easier said than done, I guess?
Families are tough.
Present company excluded, I'm assuming.
We all have our mountains
to climb.
How's his potassium?
Uh, it's low, actually.
And the diving,
he trains regularly, or...?
You think it could be related
to exertion?
If the attacks are consistent
with exercise, maybe.
Thank you, June.
- Hey, if you ever need to talk...
- We just did.
(BASHIR): You paged me?
Did you send Khaled to surgery?
Yeah, OR said one more hour, why?
I went to check on his pain
meds, he's not in his room.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC)
Excuse me. I'm sorry!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(KHALED WHEEZING)
Khaled!
Hey, hey, hey, hey,
hey, hey, hey!
Hey, hey, go get help!
Okay, stay with me, okay?
Keep your eyes open!
I need a trauma team! Patient
has flail chest, he left AMA!
I think a broken rib may
have punctured a vein.
Get him on the monitors,
107 re-breather,
we need two lines in! Dr. Hamed,
do an eFast right away.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC)
(WHEEZING)
- Pulse is dropping.
- BP 60, systolic and falling.
Okay. He needs a chest tube
stat, then get him to the OR.
(BASHIR): He's in tamponade, a
chest tube won't be enough.
There's blood in the pericardium
that's causing hemodynamic compromise.
He needs a thoracotomy.
Dr. Hamed, we'll take it
from here.
Dr. Atwater, get ready to intubate.
Claire, one hundred ketamine
one hundred sux!
We need to drain the pericardium
before it suffocates him.
- Dr. Hamed.
- Sir, please!
It's my fault he left.
- (MACHINES BEEPING RAPIDLY)
- I'll take it from here.
(KHALED COUGHING)
Here you go.
Dr. Mitchell's coming to meet you soon.
How's Laura, now?
She seems to be responding
to her medication,
but it's still early in the process.
When it happened with Sarah,
I felt so powerless.
Nothing we did seemed to help.
Well, there are more
resources available now
then when your wife was diagnosed.
We can help you connect with them.
Do you have any family in the
area who can support you?
(SIGHS)
Sister in Mississauga.
She loves Laura. She'll help.
I can take a leave of absence
from work, whatever she needs.
Her mother wouldn't
take any of the drugs.
She hated the side effects.
It was so...
hard.
(SIGHS, SOFT MUSIC)
I still think there was something
more I could have done.
You can't blame yourself.
One night with Laura's mom,
I woke up all alone.
I looked all over the house
and eventually found her
down in the basement.
She'd gone outside and dug up
every old pet rabbit that we ever had,
convinced that they were valuable.
She put them in the safe...
on top of the passports.
After that, I was with
her day and night...
until she left.
And did you hear from her again?
A year later,
the police showed up.
Sarah took her life.
I'm so sorry.
When can I see Laura?
Soon. Yes, um...
Dr. Mitchell is gonna want to
see you both of you together
to assess if you can
manage her care at home.
I'll come and get you when he's ready.
(SOFT PIANO MUSIC)
(SIGHS)
I'm so glad you called. I know
we've had our differences...
Why don't you just tell me
why you spoke to my boss?
Dr. Singh?
I had a consult with him this morning.
I didn't know he was your boss
until we started chatting.
You just happened to tell
him my entire life story?
(CHUCKLING) I barely said anything!
You knew that if you spoke to
him, it'd come back to me.
That's exactly what you wanted.
Okay. Maybe on some level
I wanted you to know.
But I'm sober. I've changed.
You've been sober before,
you didn't change then.
Do you even know why I didn't take
your money for medical school?
You were always stubborn?
Wow. (SCOFFS)
Remember you bought me
that car when I was 16,
and you said it was so I can
have my independence, right?
But then Mom left, and I realized...
you knew that was coming, right?
You were just trying
to buy me and hurt her
because you made her
fight for every penny.
So, since it's always
about what you want,
why don't you just tell me
why you're actually here?
I need to make this right.
(DISTANT SIRENS)
I have stomach cancer,
and I'm scared, okay?
I need an operation, and I...
I-I don't know what to do, June.
(CHUCKLE)
(SCOFF) You just...
You do what everyone else does.
You have the surgery, you
wait for the results...
But you do it without me.
(SOFT INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
Bashir.
Welcome back.
What happened?
When you left the hospital,
one of your broken ribs
punctured the vein
that carries blood to your heart.
I'm sorry for putting you
through this.
Don't be.
I understand why you left.
The officer?
He's still here.
I think you should talk to him.
What I said before,
about you being a doctor...
It wasn't wrong.
But it wasn't fair.
I'm glad you're a doctor.
And I know things have been
hard for you and Amira, too.
This isn't the life we planned.
But I think there's hope for us both.
(KNOCKING)
Are you okay?
I'll be here the whole time.
(SIGHS)
Thank you.
Good afternoon, Mr. Abdullah.
I'm Officer Brent, I heard
you had quite a fall.
Yes.
I'd like to ask a few questions,
if you're feeling up to it.
(DR. MITCHELL): Laura, you want to
tell your dad how you're feeling?
(MR. BAILEY): Laura,
honey, it's gonna be okay.
I know that you're scared.
But you have all these great
doctors taking care of you,
- and I'll be here for you too.
- You're not him.
You wanna tell us why you
don't think this is your dad?
Laura, I know that you're afraid.
Honey, I promise it's me.
I know your whole life.
When you lost your first tooth
at the beach, and...
we made strangers crawl
around looking for it.
When all you would eat
was bananas for a month!
Stop talking like him!
You're not him!
(DR. MITCHELL): Okay,
he's going to leave now.
Please, sir, we're gonna talk alone.
- (MAGS): Mr. Bailey.
- Please, let me stay with her.
No! Get out!
Please, I just want my real dad.
Okay? I just, I want my Mom.
- But you...
- Please, get out! Get out now!
- Please, sir.
- Get out, please!
- Come on.
- Get out!
(LAURA BREATHING HEAVILY)
(DOOR CLOSING)
I don't know where to go
from here.
You get something to eat,
some sleep,
and you come back tomorrow.
Because that's what she needs.
(MR. BAILEY CRYING)
This is day one.
They won't all be this hard. Okay?
(SOFT INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
- Ah, Mags. I've been looking for you.
- Yeah?
Uh, Dr. Bishop wants to know
if your slides are ready.
Oh. Yeah.
Of course, yeah they will be.
Great. Also, I've got
a broken leg in three,
vomiting and diarrhea in five, and
two kids who need sutures in curtas.
- Yeah. I'll take it.
- Good?
Yes, I got it.
Thanks...
(SOFT INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
(HEAVY BREATHING)
(POUNDING HEARTBEAT)
(EXHALES)
(TENSE MUSIC)
(GASPING)
(MUTED SOUNDS)
Thank you.
(MAGS EXHALING) What happened?
A nurse found you out cold
in a storage room.
- Who else knows?
- No one.
It's my...
My pacemaker is due for
a replacement soon.
I was putting it off...
Nothing to do with your heart condition.
It was the first thing I checked.
Your...
heart didn't miss a beat.
Your blood pressure,
on the other hand...
130 over 70.
Mags, you're exhausted
and dehydrated.
You're pushing yourself too hard, and
I probably ask too much from you.
Everyone has their own limits.
I'm worried that's a lesson
you refuse to learn.
I know that I've taken on
a little more than I should have,
I know...
Couple good night sleeps,
and I'll bounce back.
You're not hearing me.
What if this had happened in a trauma?
It's not lost on me the high
standards you set for yourself.
And they should be high...
- But?
- But...
Unless you can strike a balance...
Maybe the emergency
department is not for you.
You don't think I have
what it takes?
I think Internal Medicine
could use a brain like yours,
and...
it may be a better pace for you.
I want you to consider making a change.
I've spoken to Dr. Parvati.
He wanted you as his
resident in the first place,
and he's willing to let you try Internal
on a temporary basis, after
you had some time off.
Dr. Bishop, no, please.
This is...
This is the only thing I've ever wanted.
I'll find ways to improve,
I'll do, I'll do anything.
(SOFT INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
I don't want you waking up
in 20 years
and realizing this place
has swallowed you whole.
Run out the IV, and go home.
You need to rest, Mags.
You're off for the rest of the week.
And don't worry about the locum.
I found somebody to fill in.
(DOOR OPENING AND CLOSING)
(THEO): Trey has what's called
hypokalemic periodic paralysis.
- That sounds serious.
- Well, it's very rare,
and almost always happens to people
under 20 with low potassium.
Periodic meaning
it's not permanent?
The disease itself is permanent,
but the paralysis is not.
What do we do for him?
You manage it,
with diet and medication.
So he's not gonna lose
the use of his legs?
No. (SIGHS)
The muscle weakness will come and go,
but Trey should be able
to live very normally.
But he'll be able to train again?
I would recommend laying off
a few weeks,
but that'll have to be up to Trey.
Don't worry, honey,
we're gonna get you the
best physio we can.
What if I don't want that?
Buddy, it's gonna be okay. I know
you're a little freaked out, b...
No, Dad, like... It's not that.
I don't wanna dive anymore.
And if that means that you two
have to get a divorce, then...
it just has to happen.
You think
that we're gonna split up?
Aren't you?
I mean, you two basically
hate each other.
And the only thing you have
in common is my diving.
Trey, your father and I, we...
We never meant to make you
feel that way.
Well, you did.
(SOFT PIANO MUSIC)
(MOTHER): We're so sorry.
That wasn't fair of us.
(FATHER): And you should
only dive if you want to.
I thought you were gonna go
for three days straight.
I figured it's about time
I get some rest.
That doesn't sound like you.
Bash?
Does it...
Does this place feel
like home to you yet?
Mmm...
Yeah. It's starting to.
(SOFT INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC)
Ready?
Good to go. How was your day?
Long and dull.
But I guess that's a good thing.
How about you?
- Same.
- Yeah?
I mean, there was one interesting
thing that happened.
Hmm?
I, uh...
I got invited to the arcade
with my boyfriend and his son.
So, you know, there's that.
(CHUCKLING)
Uh, Dr. Bishop?
Mm-hmm?
That permanent pediatrics
opening you told me about,
is that still on the table?
I got the impression you
didn't want it. What's changed?
I did.
Turns out I do want it.
If it's not too late,
I'd like to take you up on your
offer of a recommendation.
Applications are due
at the end of next week.
Thank you, sir.
You took a risk for Bash today.
- Cops give you any trouble?
- What? I can handle a little trouble.
You've got plans tonight?
Well, there's a glass of wine
with my name on it at home.
- You?
- Mm-mm.
Hey, Claire?
Have a good night.
Don't stay here too late.
_
Hmm, football and food.
Did I tell you about my championship
game when I was 18?
- A header to win...
- In extra time.
You mentioned it once or twice.
(FOOTBALL GAME PLAYING ON PHONE)
Can you stay? Watch with me?
Only if I don't
have to hear that story again.
- Synced and corrected by martythecrazy -
- www.addic7ed.com -