So, since it's always
about what you want,
why don't you just tell me
why you're actually here?
- I have stomach cancer.
- Wasn't it three weeks ago,
I asked you to go see Doctor Mitchell?
Have you gone?
Every time I look at my sister,
I'm reminded of the one thing
I can't give her back.
Our parents.
(GUNFIRE)
(MUFFLED GUNFIRE)
(BEEPING)
You never go in.
Why is that?
I can't.
You need to face it.
For her.
(BEEPING)
(THEME MUSIC)
- Synced and corrected by martythecrazy -
- www.addic7ed.com -
There's nowhere to wash
your hands, to, you know,
he didn't have a napkin
or a handkerchief.
It was disgusting!
And anyway, we would've been
here by now if we'd driven.
Well, I like the subway,
and I'm not letting myself
get sucked into your rarified air.
Why? You might get used to it?
(LAUGHS)
Ah! Thank you!
Three injured in a car accident.
ETA six minutes.
- Great.
- Bye.
Okay, you too.
- (MOANING)
- Navia Khan. 42. Uber driver.
Crashed into a vehicle on Spadina.
The light was green.
I didn't realize she
hadn't started moving
until it was too late.
Pelvic injuries, lacerations
and a dislocated shoulder.
BP's 140 over 95, rate's 120.
Are there any traumas... (INDISTINCT)
- Was speed a factor?
- Cops said no.
Is she gonna be okay?
We're gonna take
good care of her.
Sonja Jessup was rear-ended.
34 years old. Wounds seem minor.
She cut herself on broken glass
helping the other driver
and her passenger out of their vehicle.
Doctor, have a look at Ms.
Jessup checked over.
- Use E.
- Manny Kowalski.
34 years old. Complaining
of severe abdo pain,
but there's no evidence of trauma.
His BP's 130 over 95, rate's 120,
his temp's 38.3.
Sir, I'm so sorry!
(GRUNTS) I've had worse drivers.
At least you got me to my destination.
You were trying
to get the hospital?
I had this pain in my gut
for a while.
How long have you been
having this pain, Mr. Kowalski?
A month, maybe.
But it's been getting worse.
Today it was finally bad
enough to get me to come in.
Alright, on a scale
of one to ten when I do this?
(GRUNTS) Ah! Fifteen.
Five of morphine
for Mr. Kowalski.
I swear, I'm not usually
such a snowflake.
No need to be a hero here.
Possible kidney stone?
(MOANING IN PAIN)
Positive seatbelt sign.
Claire, I need a plate.
Your shoulder's back in place,
but this wound will need to be stitched.
What did you say about
a seatbelt sign?
We're gonna do an X-ray and
an ultrasound of your pelvis.
Seatbelt pressure can sometimes
cause it to fracture.
Okay, plate in?
1, 2, 3.
- 1, 2, 3.
- (MOANING)
Exposing!
Plate out. 1, 2, 3.
1, 2, 3.
X-ray's up!
There's free fluid
in the pelvis,
but no fracture, that's strange.
They usually go hand in hand.
I'll try a blind Foley.
What does that mean?
There might be a tear in your bladder
from the force of the seat belt.
I'm going to place a catheter.
If it comes back with urine,
we'll know your bladder's
intact and a tear's unlikely.
- Claire?
- On it.
(MOANING)
Complex fluid collection
in the abdominal cavity.
Dr. Bishop, I'm seeing debris.
Sir, have you had
open surgery recently?
- I had a hernia removed.
- Here?
Another hospital.
But that was like a year ago.
Why? Is something wrong?
We'll X-ray
and have a closer look.
Give me the plate.
Thank God I had already
dropped my kids off at school.
If they'd been in the
car and gotten hurt...
Ow!
Sorry.
Well, uh, nothing seems to be broken,
though soft tissue injuries are
common after a car collision.
I can give you something
for the discomfort.
No, this is, uh, nothing new.
I've had back pain for years.
Okay. Can I just see your hands?
Sure.
It's not too bad.
Still, we should do some imaging.
Is there someone we can call?
- My husband's on his way.
- Great.
No urine.
- Probable rupture.
- Can you fix that?
Well, we'll confirm with a CT.
Then, you'll need a surgical consult.
I'll page Urology.
We'll take good care of you.
Those have been in there
for a year?
This only makes sense
with the information...
What's been in where?
Sir, whoever performed
your hernia operation
left two surgical sponges behind.
You're telling me that they
forgot something inside of me?
It would explain your infection,
your fever, your stomach pain.
We're gonna get you to
surgery as soon as we can.
Two grams of Ampi, IV-stat.
(BASHIR): Deep breath.
And again.
Sonja?
Sonja!
Can you hear me?
(GASPS)
You lost consciousness, Ms. Jessup.
Your respiration rate's low.
Do you remember hitting your head?
- Any headache?
- No.
Um, I'm just dizzy.
Uh, it's probably from all the blood.
I'm fine, I'm sure.
I'm sure it's nothing.
Easy, easy, easy.
Just... take a second.
I'm going to order a CT scan
to rule out any intercranial injury,
also get some blood work done
to make sure there's
nothing else going on.
- Okay?
- Okay.
Alright, I'll be right back.
Really?
Complicated differential?
No, not exactly.
I got invited to this party,
like, old friends from med school.
- I should go, but I...
- Don't wanna go alone?
Sounds like you need a buffer.
Not my thing.
What about, uh... Hmm!
No, no, no.
No one from Neurology. No.
He sings when he cuts.
I don't think going with a
random is the way to go,
Hmm?
Hey, what are you doing here?
Hey! My surgery is today.
Well, that's on the sixth floor.
That's not down here.
I called your brother.
He didn't want to come up from Chicago.
Elevators are down the hall.
June!
Hey.
That looked intense.
- You okay?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
Who was that guy?
Hmm?
That's my father.
Okay.
He's not a patient here, is he?
Is everything okay?
Apart from being a giant prick?
He has stomach cancer and
Singh's his surgeon.
Okay, so your father's sick
and your boss is his surgeon?
Why wouldn't you tell
me something like that?
I told you that my dad and I
don't talk.
Which means you and I
don't either?
Look, June,
I get that your
relationship's messed up,
and you don't like to talk about it.
But you can't just shut me out
of big chunks of your life.
It makes me feel like you
don't want me in it at all.
Lou, trust me.
I'm doing you a favor, okay?
- That guy...
- Well, maybe I don't need you to.
Lou!
Excuse me, Doctor?
I'm, uh, Jason.
Sonja Jessup's husband.
Bashir Hamed.
Uh, she said she was rear-ended.
- Is that true?
- Yes.
And she's, um, she's okay?
We're running some tests
to make sure.
Uh, Dr. Hamed,
did Sonja ask you for painkillers?
She's managing fine.
If she does ask for some,
please don't give her any.
Sir?
My wife's an opioid addict.
She's been clean six months.
It's important you don't
even offer her any.
Thank you.
♪
Mags?
Does this CT look normal to you?
Yeah.
Yeah, I don't think your
patient sustained head trauma.
Doesn't seem like it
from her scan,
but she passed out
during the physical exam
- and her respiratory rate is low.
- You have a theory?
Her husband just told me
she's had problems with opioids.
Did you run blood work?
Labs aren't back yet,
but according to her chart,
she was here a couple of
times eight months ago
requesting narcotics for back pain.
The last doctor she saw here
wouldn't prescribe any.
Did she ask for any today?
No, even though
she's clearly in pain.
She probably knows
that she's flagged.
Doesn't wanna draw attention to it.
Decreased resp rate, losing
consciousness, no head trauma?
Her husband said
she's clean now.
Still, it's kind of tough to ignore
what those symptoms are saying
That she's using again.
I called the surgeons who
repaired Mr. Kowalski's hernia.
Bet they called their lawyer
as soon as you hung up.
Wife and kids are downstairs.
She said she tried to get him come
over but he kept pulling it off.
Speaking of your father's on the
board for his gastrectomy today.
You're welcome to observe.
Obviously, we can't
have you scrubbing in,
- but...
- No, thank you.
Understood. Better stay busy.
You'll have plenty to do
once your dad's home anyway.
He said how grateful he was
you're willing to look after him.
He told you
he was staying with me?
Pretty sure my wife and daughter would
pay someone to take me off their hands.
Urology should be down
as soon as they can.
Okay, any pain here?
(MOANING) It was way
worse the first time.
You've dislocated it before?
- When?
- Last year.
I was reaching into the crawlspace.
My husband took one look
at it dangling there
and almost fainted.
Ex-husband I should say.
I'm still not used to
saying that out loud.
Surgery to repair my bladder.
Scale of one-to-ten,
how big a deal is it?
It's laparoscopic, so recovery
shouldn't be too bad.
But having a friend or family member
around is always a good idea.
Thing is,
I just moved to Toronto,
so I don't really know anyone here yet.
When my husband quit our marriage,
I quit the office job I always hated.
Gave myself a year to start
over and open a food truck.
- That's pretty brave.
- Brave and stupid.
I've been driving Uber
to keep things afloat.
Oh.
Sorry.
Your stitches tore through your skin.
Have you been moving around a lot?
I'm guessing that's not
supposed to happen?
Don't worry. I'll re-suture,
and then, uh, we'll figure it out.
Why weren't you moving
if the light turned green?
You're always the one honking
to go before it even changes.
It was green barely a second
before she hit me.
Good news, your CT came back
negative for any head injury.
Great, but if she didn't
actually hit her head,
why did you check it?
He... He's just being thorough.
- I'll give you guys some space.
- No, please.
What aren't you telling me?
Nothing.
Sonja?
I, um, I passed out earlier.
You passed out?
In the accident?
No, when I got here
and I didn't want to tell you
because I didn't want you to worry.
Are you using again?
No, Jason! I swear.
Then why didn't you tell me
you passed out? Why lie?
Because I was afraid you were gonna
jump to this exact conclusion.
Or because you were high
and that's why you didn't
see the light change.
No, I wasn't!
I was distracted for, like, a second
and then she slammed into me!
You drove the kids this morning.
Did you get high and drive the kids?
No, Jason!
- You have to believe me!
- How can I?
After everything we've been through?
- Because I wouldn't do that...
- Except you have!
When you picked up Tessa from dance!
Her carpool got messed up
and she was by herself!
Excuses! My God!
Look, I know things
were messed up, Jason!
But I swore to you I
wouldn't do it again!
But you did! And you knew
this was your last chance!
Gosh, I should have seen it.
You've been distant lately.
Barely present.
Yeah, because I've been in pain!
I wasn't using!
I wanted to, Jay, but I didn't!
I didn't even ask the
doctor for painkillers.
That doesn't mean you didn't
take something before.
That's what you're waiting for the
test results to prove, right?
The labs could tell us
a number of different things.
You promised we were done
with this!
You're out of chances.
Jason, don't...
- Don't do this, just, just...
- Don't come home tonight.
I don't want you around
our kids anymore.
Jason, wait!
Oh, I'm gonna be sick.
(MOANING)
- I'll get you on fluids.
- I don't need fluids.
We have resources
that can help you.
- There's a detox nurse on staff.
- No!
I can get you Suboxone
for withdrawal.
I said no!
I don't want your help.
A doctor like you gave me
pain meds in the first place
and got me into this mess.
I'm sorry.
I'll be back with your lab results.
Dr. Hamed.
Your sister's school called
and it sounded urgent.
Go.
- We'll cover if we have to.
- Thank you.
I need to add labs
for Navia Khan.
- That's the bladder rupture?
- Yeah.
Isn't she just waiting
for her Urology consult?
I know you don't want me
overdiagnosing,
but her stitches tore
right through her skin
despite a lack of physical motion.
- She's also bruising easily...
- Dr. Leblanc.
No, true, neither of those
things point anything concrete,
but something in the way
her bladder ruptured,
even without pelvic fracture
was already bothering me...
I agree! I read her chart.
Didn't she also have a shoulder
dislocation from the accident?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
A history of them, actually.
Do you think that's connected?
I think you should look into it.
- Keep me in the loop.
- I'll call the lab.
I think you have created a
monster in your own image.
One day, we are all gonna be
working for Mags.
Thanks so much for coming in.
We were making family trees in class.
Amira didn't want to make hers.
I guess her classmate
Candace made a comment
about her not doing one
and things got heated.
Candace started shoving first...
- Are they okay?
- They're both fine.
We asked the girls to apologize.
Candace did, but Amira
said there was no point
since she'd be going back
to Syria soon anyway.
I don't know
why she would say that.
She knows it's not true.
Is anything going on at home
that might be affecting her mood?
We're moving apartments again,
and...
I know she's not too thrilled about it,
but maybe it's affecting
her more than I realized.
At this age,
it's easier for them to hide
when things aren't going well.
Lately, she's been withdrawn,
not turning in assignments...
So she's not doing her homework?
I'm concerned Amira's
holding a lot in.
(PATIENT): Give me the blue one, bud.
Thanks.
Hey!
I know they said
I should be resting,
but this is the best medicine
that I could hope for.
Okay, well, I just came
to let you guys know that
everything went well.
We took out the sponges, and
cleared the infected tissue.
I thought it was indigestion.
I can't believe there was
something rotting inside me.
He didn't want to have
the hernia surgery either,
but he had been in pain
so long, so I pushed him.
Emily, hon, you couldn't have
known this would happen.
Help me out here, doc!
Manny's right. This is
what we call a never event.
As in, it never should've happened.
I don't wanna waste any time
dwelling on the negative.
Cameron has his soccer
tournament next weekend.
You need to take care of yourself.
Cam and I need you healthy.
Look, you just
get some rest, okay?
Let your body heal.
And take care of your dad, alright?
Alright.
I'll check on you guys later.
Thank you.
Your teacher tells me
you pushed another student.
She pushed me first!
That doesn't mean you push back.
If you're having issues at school,
you need to be honest with me.
I know you don't want
to move apartments,
is that why you've been upset?
If we leave Theo's, it's just
gonna be us again, and...
I won't have anyone to talk to.
Amira, that's not true.
You can talk to me!
Hmm?
Why don't you tell me what
happened with the family tree?
They called me in the middle of the day,
telling me that you've been in a fight,
that you're not doing your assignments.
And you know you can't go back to Syria,
why are you telling people we are?
Because I wish we were!
I hate it here!
You hate it here?
You know you are the
only reason we're here!
The only reason I came!
How could I know that?
You say we should be honest,
but we're not! We never are!
I'm sorry.
Would you... do you want to come
back to the hospital with me?
I have detention.
Sorry they bothered you at work.
Trauma bag has naloxone,
epi, atropine,
and gear for surgical airway.
Thanks for letting me
tag along to log my hours.
Yeah, I guess congratulations
are in order.
Have you moved your family here already?
We're still, uh,
we're just trying to figure out
how all that's gonna work.
Well, get ready to test
your mettle.
What's Sudbury, like four hours by car?
How long do you think you're go to
be doing the back and forth thing?
Uh, as long as I need to, I guess.
Your wife doesn't wanna
move here?
I kind of took the offer
before really discussing it with her.
Ah, so you're an idiot.
Why did you do that?
Because I wanted it.
Yeah, I thought I was
taking control of my life,
- but I guess I was just...
- Avoiding the conflict.
Yeah. I hoped she'd come around,
but she hasn't and if
I walk it back now...
Hmm, it won't be the same.
She'll always wonder
if you just settled.
Yeah.
Hello, sir. 9-1-1 response?
Are you sure you got
the right address?
2319 Berkley.
We got a call about a minor
with a wrist injury?
A minor with a wrist injury.
Um, I didn't know that he called.
Come on in.
Benjamin! Can you come
down here, please?
Hey, buddy!
Did you call 9-1-1?
Why didn't you tell me
you were doing that?
Hi, Benjamin!
I'm Joanie. This is Theo.
- Hi.
- No school today?
Our school had a PA day.
Which means since Mom's
out of town,
Dad gets to work from home today.
You wanna tell us
what happened here?
I'd managed to coax him away
from his video games.
And, um, we went outside,
toss the football around,
and after about 10 minutes,
Ben fell on his wrist.
Ouch.
Well, can we agree
that calling in the cavalry
was a bit of an overreaction?
I'm sure these two have
more important calls
they should be responding too, hmm?
Sorry.
Actually, you guys are in luck.
Theo's a pediatrician, so he
can check you out right now
and you may not even need
to go to the hospital.
Great.
Yeah, why don't you
take a seat, bud?
Sir, do you have
your son's health card?
There's some information
I need to note down.
Uh, yeah.
You mind if I take a look?
Yeah?
I want you to tell me where
it hurts the most, okay.
My dad was just trying
to show me how to take a tackle.
He didn't mean for me to get hurt.
(MOANING)
Now, you've been hurt
playing sports with him before?
Broke a couple fingers once.
There.
It hurts there the most.
Alright, Benjamin...
Does your dad play a
little rough with you?
No, it's okay.
Some people just play differently
and they don't realize it.
He says I need to toughen up.
Hey, Bash. Bishop asked me
to cover for your patients.
Said you had to step out.
Are you okay? Is everything okay?
Everything's fine.
Did Sonja Jessup's blood work come back?
Yes, but not before she left.
A nurse tried to stop her,
but she wouldn't stay.
I wish she'd change her mind,
let us get her some help.
Actually, um, she didn't have
any opioids in her system.
You're saying Sonja
wasn't using?
Blood work was clean. Yeah.
I tried treating her
for withdrawal.
I didn't believe her. No
wonder she didn't stay.
It was a reasonable
assumption to make.
Yeah, but that means there's
something else wrong with her.
(BANGING)
(HEART MONITOR BEEPING)
What happened?
A massive embolism.
Clot blocked the blood
flow to his heart.
He arrested immediately.
Code blue team did everything
they could to bring him back,
but nothing.
There were no warning signs?
We had him on anti-coags,
but when it's this big and sudden,
there's nothing we can do.
His wife and kid.
I'll talk to them.
- No. I can handle it.
- I know you can.
But you've got enough going
on today with your dad.
He's in recovery. You can go see him.
(SOBBING)
Looks like we'll have to take
that trip to Memorial after all.
So, it is broken.
We need an X-ray to be sure,
but it looks that way.
Ah. You'll be okay, Ben.
We just need to wait
for the police to arrive.
You called the police?
They respond to every 9-1-1 call.
We just got here first.
They'll need you to
give them a statement.
Okay, about what? His wrist?
Yes. How it happened.
I'm sorry, Dad. I didn't know
the police would come.
It's okay, it's okay.
I'll tell them it was an accident!
Ben! That's enough!
Look, I don't think there's any need
to make a statement to the police.
Well, when a minor's involved,
there is.
We were just horsing around.
Kids fall all the time.
Maybe, but the fact is
Benjamin broke his wrist
when you tackled him.
The police are gonna need
to hear what happened.
Okay. So, if we're gonna
go to the hospital,
then I'm gonna take him there myself.
Alright? Let's go, Ben.
Sir, let's just
wait for the police.
- Get out of my way.
- Dad, don't!
Quiet!
Move.
I said move!
You're scaring your son.
Lower your voice and
wait for the police.
Everything okay in here?
Is it?
This is ridiculous.
Navia Khan has a history
of muscle pain and weakness.
At first, I worried it could be MS,
but urinalysis and CBC were negative.
And it wouldn't explain
the ruptured bladder.
Her bruising is extensive,
but her passenger didn't sustain any.
She also has skin atrophy,
which explains the stitches tearing.
Did you check for benign
growths on pressure areas,
- elbows, knees, or even...
- Heart valve problems?
Ehlers-Danlos Syndrome.
Most cases of Ehlers-Danlos
take years to diagnose.
If you're right, you saved her a decade
of not knowing what was wrong with her.
Sir, this kind of thing...
Is exactly what I told you
not to get sucked into?
It's hard to find the line.
Yeah. I know it is.
I'll get an echo
and order a skin biopsy
to confirm the diagnosis.
Good work, Dr. Leblanc.
33-year-old woman
collapsed in a coffee shop!
She was unconscious when we arrived.
We administered Naloxone at the scene.
Sonja Jessup.
She overdosed?
Do we know what she took?
BP's dropping.
Heart rate's 145.
- She's in V-Tach.
- She shouldn't be.
I mean, heart rate decreases
after an overdose.
Isn't this your car accident victim
that walked out AMA this morning?
She lost consciousness
during the physical exam
and her resp rate was low, but
she wasn't on opioids then.
Muffled heart sounds. Scan!
Cardiac tamponade.
She needs a pericardiocentesis.
We need to drain the
fluid around her heart.
Okay. Do it.
I need an 18 gauge 7cm needle
with a 30CC syringe.
Got it.
I see the trajectory.
Claire, keep the field in view.
Use the subside forward
approach.
And aim towards the left shoulder.
SATS are falling.
I don't feel it yet.
Go easy. You're not quite in.
Got it.
She's stabilizing.
I let her leave.
This is on me.
Sonja left the hospital and OD'd?!
She's stable now.
Okay? Here.
This is what I've been dreading.
This is my worst nightmare.
Jason,
you should also know that...
there were no opioids in
her system this morning.
You're saying...
she wasn't high when she drove the kids?
Well that means,
she only went and used
after I accused her?
This is my fault!
I told her not to come home!
She could've died!
But she didn't.
She's sedated right now, but
you'll be able to see her soon.
Okay?
It wasn't the car accident
that caused my bladder to rupture?
It was this other thing?
Well, it was a combination
of the two things,
but if you hadn't been
in the car accident,
we may never have found out,
because it meant several
of your symptoms
presented at once.
And this condition.
Ehlers-Danlos?
- Is it serious?
- It can be.
Your joints dislocate more often.
You bruise easily.
You might experience
extreme muscle pain,
or be prone to ruptured organs,
like your bladder.
But the good news is
it's not degenerative,
so it's not gonna get worse.
But there's no cure.
So I'll have it forever?
I'm sorry, Navia.
I know it's not...
It's not what you were
expecting to hear.
I convinced myself
I was strong enough
to throw everything out and
start this big adventure.
And now, you're telling me I'm broken,
fragile, and there's
nothing I can do about it?
You can be prepared.
Watch for any warning signs.
Be more careful in your
day-to-day activities.
I never should have left home.
Now I'm alone with this.
Hey, Ben.
How's your arm?
I heard your mom's on her way back.
They said my Dad might not get
to come home tonight.
It's all my fault.
Ben, none of this is your fault.
If I was tougher,
this wouldn't be happening!
When your dad plays rough
with you like that,
it's not okay.
It has nothing to do
with how tough you are.
(CRYING)
The father's
a real piece of work.
Insists the kid just landed wrong.
Ben landed where his dad
tackled him.
And he's pretty upset about it.
Thinks he's got his dad into trouble.
His dad got himself
into trouble.
Let's hope he smartens himself up.
Last chance to back out.
Welcome to the team.
(TELEVISION PLAYING)
Why did you tell Singh
you were coming to stay with me?
I'm fine.
Thanks for asking.
Yeah, I know.
I checked your chart.
It got your attention,
didn't it?
You're unbelievable.
I...
I hoped you might say yes, okay?
I know you hate me.
That you haven't forgiven
me for my mistakes.
I'm all alone here, June.
Don't put that on me.
You're alone because
you've hurt everyone
who's ever cared about you.
Yeah.
You're right.
You know, I'm stronger
than I used to be.
I'm not just gonna let
you do that to me again.
I don't wanna hurt you, June.
I wanna be in your life.
Every time I let you in,
I'm the one who ends up paying.
(SIGHING)
Maybe it was like that before,
but now...
You know, you say you've changed,
but you lied to my boss!
You lied to my boss to
get me to talk to you?
Okay, that was, um,
that was a mistake.
- I can do better.
- I don't think you can.
And even if you could,
I don't think I can give
you another chance, so...
(CRYING)
So, uh..
You know, Dr. Singh's a great doctor.
And if you need anything at home,
I will find you a nurse.
But that's all.
You know, I've see all kinds,
working here.
All kinds of love.
Seen people lose families
and find families.
But that's just not who we are.
(COUGHING)
Hi.
Your husband was just here.
He's making arrangements
for the kids.
I...
I didn't believe you, Sonja.
I'm... I'm sorry.
Turns out you were right not to.
You stopped once.
You can stop again.
Yeah, but the pain
never goes away.
One bad moment sends me over the edge.
I know my family keeps hoping
that this is over, but...
it's never over.
Now, when I look at my life,
all I see is this void.
This giant void.
You have to face it.
What if I can't?
What if I'm not strong enough?
But you are.
(PHONE CHIMING)
_
Hey!
- You're back?
- Yeah.
I went to this party, but...
I can't stop thinking about my patient.
I told her she had Ehlers-Danlos today,
and she took it pretty hard.
I came back, because...
Because you're Mags,
so what do you do?
Yeah.
Hi.
I heard your surgery went well.
You should be going home tomorrow.
They said you were gone.
Yeah.
I know what it's like.
Feeling fragile.
And questioning what you're...
what you're capable of.
I left everything I knew
to come here.
Follow my passion. And now...
You'll make some adjustments.
The only way to know how is to try.
So tell me about your food truck.
Seriously?
I don't know that much
about food trucks,
other than I like eating at them! A lot.
But I've got nowhere else to be,
and I'd love to learn more,
if you want the company.
Okay.
- Well, when I was eight...
- Mm-hmm?
My parents used to take me
travelling, a lot...
June, I've been calling you!
I thought we had dinner plans!
Yeah, I just figured
you were still mad.
Yeah, so, we hash it out.
That's how this works, right?
I think we should end this.
Okay, whoa,
where did that come from?
You were right, Lou.
I don't let you in.
Not you or anyone. I can't.
- If this is about your dad...
- It's about me.
It's about me, alright?
Maybe it's because of him,
or maybe it's who I always was,
but I'm not good at this.
- And I'm just gonna hurt you.
- You're not him, June.
This kind of stuff
takes practice, right?
Don't do this.
You deserve better.
June, wait!
- Please.
- I'm sorry!
You wanted to see me,
Dr. Bishop?
Yeah, come in. Close the door.
About Sonja Jessup, um,
it was my fault.
She left before we could...
We can't keep patients
here against their will.
What happened with Amira?
Was everything okay?
Uh, yeah,
there was some drama at school,
but, uh, she's fine.
There was an incident
with another student.
I tried talking to her,
but I guess I'm saying
all the wrong things.
She's 12?
When my son was 12...
It gets harder.
Knowing what to say.
Main thing is, you're
there when she needs you.
That's a lesson I learned too late.
Don't make the same mistake I did.
Thank you.
(PAGER BEEPING)
It's ICU. Sonja Jessup is crashing.
SATS are low, but her heart
rate is through the roof again.
Get her on a non-rebreather.
Dr. Hamed, let's get eyes in her chest.
Have we got her blood work back?
Not yet!
So we still don't know
what we're dealing with.
Massive pleural effusion.
Sonja, you have fluid
on your lungs.
We're going to put a chest
tube in to help you breathe.
Alright?
We'll take good care of you.
Okay.
Scalpel.
Making primary incision.
30 "emo stat".
Performing blood dissection
through the muscle in fashion.
Chest tube.
- Inserting chest tube.
- Mm-hmm.
Guide me through placement.
A millimeter left.
Just a millimiter.
I can't feel the pleural space.
Am I close?
Sir?
Dr. Bishop?
Keep going.
Okay.
- What?
- I think I nicked something.
Guys?
Placement was wrong.
I think I perforated an organ.
We've got a bleed.
Ease out, nice and slow.
Slowly. Slowly.
SATS are falling!
He's gonna need a new tube,
Claire.
Pressure's dropping.
There's free fluid
in the abdomen.
Her spleen is ruptured.
Activate massive transfusion protocol!
Get me another chest tube!
Call for blood!
(HEART MONITOR BEEPING)
- Synced and corrected by martythecrazy -
- www.addic7ed.com -
Bash is now on the hook.
A patient's life is at risk.
- You are not taking care of yourself.
- All right Claire, all right.
My fault. My mistake.
♪
Sir?
Jed, what happened?
Everyone clear!
♪
Dr. Bishop!
THE SHOCKING SEASON FINALE
OF CTV'S TRANSPLANT.
GET INTO IT AT A SPECIAL TIME.