Oh, sorry.
Dinner, my place?
I thought we finished with all
that about five years ago.
(MUFFLED): Dr. Hamed?
(MAGS): Bash.
(GUNFIRE)
(MAN SHOUTING)
(WOMAN CRYING)
(GUNFIRE)
(MAN SHOUTING IN DISTANCE)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC)
(COUGHING)
(MAN OVER PA SYSTEM): Lockdown.
Code silver.
Lockdown. Code Silver.
Can I help?
No. I got it. It's fine. Go.
I'll go find some gauze
and come right back.
No. There's gauze in the cabinet.
I can make it. Go.
You'll be okay, I can stop the bleeding
as soon as the shooter clears.
(WOMAN GROANING)
(BASHIR): You're going to be okay.
(GUNFIRE)
(MAN SHOUTING IN DISTANCE)
(WOMAN SOBBING)
Can you move?
(INDISTINCT WHISPERING)
(LOU): Did you see him?
The last shots came from hallway J.
- You shouldn't be in the open.
- (MAGS): Are you okay?
I've got a through-and-through
to the neck.
Another in the thigh.
Mine's an abdominal wound and
a shot to the right humerus.
I applied a tourniquet to try
and stabilize his pressure,
but it's still dropping in critical.
Pressure right there.
There might not be anything
else you can do for him.
Well, maybe if I...
Maybe if I bolus him with fluids,
we'll keep him going until we
can activate massive contusion.
- (GUNFIRE)
- Get down, get down.
(MACHINES BEEPING)
(GASPING)
(HIGH-PITCHED RINGING)
(WOMAN OVER PA SYSTEM): Lights on.
That concludes the active shooter drill.
- God...
- Thank you everyone.
Well, I lost mine, how'd you
manage to stabilize yours?
Bash?
Hey, don't worry, I was going
to die no matter what you did.
(SOFT PIANO MUSIC)
And now we find out how we did.
My guy was gonna die all along.
If I had no hope of saving
him, what was the point?
Maybe that was the point.
To see how you'd handle it.
- Well then, I failed.
- Pretty sure it's not pass or fail.
Whole purpose of the
drill is to make sure
we're prepared for the real thing.
(BISHOP): Alright, thanks.
We're gonna have a full post-mortem
with the observers tomorrow.
We're gonna review the tape,
and we're gonna discuss any
course corrections in depth.
In the interim,
I want you to think about how
you're feeling right now.
And how you responded to the
situations you've faced.
You were trying to solve a
problem that couldn't be solved.
You should've called that
patient and moved on.
Learn to control what you can,
and let go of what you can't.
Right? You're an island.
But you work on a team.
You could've stopped
the bleeding quicker
if you'd let Dr. Hamed
help you get supplies.
Calm under pressure, no surprise
there, but you took huge risks.
You can't save lives if
you've sacrificed your own.
Huh? Alright.
(SOFT MUSIC)
- Synced and corrected by martythecrazy -
- www.addic7ed.com -
(ELEVATOR DINGING)
Changed your mind?
I... I pressed the wrong button.
Heard there was an active
shooter drill today.
Always cracks a few residents.
Did your patient fake die?
Fake lived, actually.
(SIGHING)
Mr. Gomes?
I'm Dr. Hamed.
I understand you've
been experiencing some
chest pains and dizziness.
- When did this start?
- Earlier this week.
I was trying to ignore it,
but I think that was a
bad idea because...
now my left arm is tingling.
Deep breath.
It can't be... it can't be
a heart attack, right?
I mean, I'm too young.
Are you a smoker, Mr. Gomes?
Kevin. No, never.
I got scared straight by that
shrivelled lung they
showed us in sixth grade.
Any family history
of heart problems?
Not that I know of.
They don't keep me in
the loop on everything.
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
Hello, I'm Dr. Leblanc.
You're from Station
19 around the corner?
Take a deep breath.
Best post I've had.
Busy, though. We stretched
three times last night.
Mm.
Do you wear a respirator?
The tanks are only good
for 20 minutes,
sometimes we're in longer.
They're heavy, so we just
ditch them when they run out.
Did you run out last night?
Yeah.
We pulled a couple
from a bad house fire.
Got in as fast as we could,
but they didn't make it.
Have you ever been diagnosed
with high blood pressure?
No. I eat right, I exercise,
I don't drink.
I just can't catch a break right now.
First I, uh... First I
lose my job, and then...
And then I had to move.
(LABOURED BREATHING)
Deep breath. Deep breath.
(SOFT MUSIC)
Alright. Your blood pressure is high,
and your heart rate has
elevated since you got here.
Is that what you were feeling before?
What do you... What do you
think is wrong with me?
Um, we'll order some tests.
Uh, some blood work
and an ECG, and uh...
Try not to worry, this
is standard procedure.
Right. Thanks, Doc.
My dad was a firefighter,
and he always said you
save the next one.
Yeah.
Okay.
Mm. Your nails are blue.
How long have they been like that?
They are? I dunno.
And your O2 sats are 88%.
I want to send you for
pulmonary function testing.
I've been doing this ten years.
I bounce back every time.
Yeah, I don't doubt it.
But you're here now,
so better be safe than sorry, right?
(COUGHS)
If the thing you loved
was slowly killing you,
would you, A, stop and save yourself,
or B, continue and risk it?
I would decide not to follow
you down this particular
rabbit hole today.
Oh my God, it's your birthday!
I baked cupcakes and I
totally forgot about them.
When do you have time to bake?
I know, I needed
something to relax me.
You know what could
help you to relax? Sleeping.
- Did you do something special?
- Mel threw the annual barbecue.
Some friends, some family,
some coconut cream pie.
- Oh, that's nice.
- It was.
You know, usual suspects.
We should shake things up
and let's go for drinks tonight.
- A kid in four is waiting for you.
- Okay?
How'd this happened?
Rolled it during soccer
practice, and wiped out.
Could've walked it off, but
Coach forced me to come.
My mom's on her way.
You should consider a beard.
Beards are in. Plus it'll
help with your chin.
Okay, good to know.
How's the pain on a scale from 1 to 10?
Six.
Eight when you do that!
Well, it's probably a sprain,
but we'll X-ray.
Either way, you're
gonna have to rest it.
But playoffs are coming up.
But you gotta think long-term.
You push it now, it could
only make it worse.
And uh, I'll get a nurse in
here disinfect these scrapes.
- Does it hurt when I press?
- No. All good.
What happened to your ribs?
Nothing. They're fine.
Danny is binding.
If it wasn't on the chart, I'd never
have known he was born a girl.
What did he say?
Not much,
he clammed up when I asked
about the tensor bandage.
I'm worried he's cutting
off circulation.
What's the protocol?
Is this your first
transgender patient?
No, I saw some adults
when I was doing residency,
but never someone this young.
But I'm just treating this
kid for a sprained ankle.
He may not have anyone
he trusts to help him with this.
(SOUNDS MUFFLING)
(HIGH-PITCHED RINGING)
(SOUNDS RETURNING TO NORMAL)
Sorry.
Sir, you really have
to hold still, okay? Ah!!
(BASHIR): Uh, nurse?
Ugh... So stupid.
I should've had security there.
Dr. Curtis, are you okay?
Yeah, just blood splatter
from a displaced IV.
The patient is an intravenous
user.
You need to fill out
an incident report.
Get blood work on him,
including HIV, Hep B, Hep C.
I want you to start PEP immediately.
Uh, I have surgery today, so...
Not anymore.
- I can draw your blood.
- I'll go to the lab.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC)
Blood work is normal, as is your ECG,
so no evidence of a heart attack.
Then what was I feeling?
You're tachycardic, which means
you have an elevated heart rate.
Is that serious?
We need to determine
the underlying cause.
Do you still feel numbness?
It... It comes and goes,
along with this splitting headache.
Well, the next step is an echo
and then a stress test, but...
What's happening to me?
Kevin?
(HIGH-PITCHED RINGING)
(MUFFLED): I need help over here!
You were saying something
about an X-ray?
We'll get you one right away,
now just give me a minute.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC)
Kevin Gomes, the heart patient.
Is he in the echo lab?
Uh no, you sent him
for a CT to rule out stroke.
When?
About an hour ago.
Arnold, have you seen
my patient Kevin Gomes?
Porters are bringing him
back down.
Why, thought you lost him?
No, just uh...
Hey, you forget something bud?
- You left this in the lounge.
- Thank you.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC)
I'm Amanda Gomes,
you left me a message?
Uh, Dr. Hamed. You're Kevin
Gomes's emergency contact?
His sister, yes. Is he okay?
I'm just about to pick up
his latest test results.
Did Kevin ask you to call me?
It's protocol when somebody
loses consciousness.
He lost consciousness?
What happened? Where is he?
Um, if you check at the nurse's desk,
they'll be able to direct you.
I'll be there shortly.
Why did you even come here?
I want to help you!
You being here only makes things worse!
If you really want to
help me, you'll leave.
Take care of him.
You called my sister?
You collapsed. We had her
on file from a prior visit...
You shouldn't have called her.
My family is...
They don't know how to
handle this kind of thing.
Well, good news,
your CT came back clear.
No sign of a stroke.
But we still don't know
why I passed out?
It could be a cardiogenic syncope.
Sometimes with an irregular heartbeat,
your blood pressure drops suddenly.
Is your headache worse?
Like a dull creeping ache
across the back of my skull.
Could you have missed something?
Doctors make mistakes
all the time, right?
Uh, we'll order an MRI.
It can detect subtleties
that sometimes a CT can't.
Four weeks. No training.
Seriously? That's like forever.
It'll fly by before you know it.
But listen...
When you rewrap your other tensor,
go easy.
Too tight, and it can
cause other problems.
Too loose, and they'll still show.
You can buy compression
chest binders.
They are easier on your skin.
Still, you shouldn't wear them
more than eight hours a day.
Yeah, but...
you need a credit card
to buy them online.
So your parents don't know
that you're...
A boy?
They're fine with the pronouns
and keeping my hair short, and
wearing boy's clothes, but...
that's about it.
They don't know that you bind.
I don't know,
we don't talk about it.
I know about gender dysphoria.
I've seen a therapist a
couple times for it.
Okay.
Is there anything I can do to help?
I want top surgery.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC)
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
Okay, Danny wants
a double mastectomy.
He asked you to help him get it?
Thirteen's pretty young to make
a call on gender reassignment.
So, you're on the conservative
side of the medical?
The kid is still growing.
And we don't have proper
long-term studies on hormones.
If he's considering it,
he should know the risks.
Hmm, well, it's a little outside
the lines of emergency medicine.
You sure you want to wade into this?
I want to make sure
he has the support he needs.
When the mother comes in, I'd...
I'd like to talk to her.
Well, let me know what you need.
(INDISTINCT BACKGROUND CHATTERING)
Does your patient know
what triggered this event?
He thinks so.
And you said he lost time.
About an hour's worth.
He can't remember
anything over that span.
Well, sounds like
a dissociative event.
Right.
He retraced his steps,
and he functioned perfectly throughout.
No one even noticed.
With dissociation, the patient's
emotional centre detaches
but his decision-making and
instincts remain the same.
Is this something he has a history of?
Sometimes he says he zones out.
But no, nothing like this.
Normally when I'm being
referred to a patient,
there's a chart of some kind.
- I'm just gathering information.
- Mm.
You said you have
experience with PTSD.
Yes, I do, and with
post-traumatic stress injuries,
the only way out is through.
You should encourage your
patient to get therapy.
And if he's not ready for that?
Well, does he have
a good support system?
Family, friends?
(DISTANT SIRENS)
He would rather not involve them.
Mm. Well, maybe he should start.
Why are you looking at the
discharged patients' files?
I'm checking to make sure
there's nothing I missed today.
Sometimes it... it all feels
like it all blends together
Mm. I'd trade you if I could.
I remember every patient.
Every detail. It's like a curse.
Can't remember what I had
for breakfast, though.
(MAGS CHUCKLING)
I can help you review if you want.
If you're worried you missed something.
Doesn't look like I did.
Did you get your antivirals?
Check.
Why are you still here?
You can't see patients.
- I have files to finish.
- We can cover that.
Why? If I have something,
I'm gonna have it at home too.
Hey, your results are in
from Respiratory.
Perfect.
- Absolutely not.
- Jessica.
Last night was a grind. I came
in for O2 and an all-clear.
I'm not sidelining myself.
Jessica, you may have COPD.
You said my chest X-ray
was clear of cancer.
That's good enough for me.
Your lung capacity is
significantly reduced.
Ignoring this could actually kill you.
- Well, so could a fire.
- Listen, it's just a few tests!
It's a consult with
one of our respirologists.
Let me help you get this under control.
Look, I know you're doing
your job, but I gotta do mine.
My dad did this job 'til he was
50, I'm not about to give it up.
Well, if you leave
against medical advice,
I need you to sign something that
says you understand the risks.
No problem.
I'm sorry, he shouldn't
have gotten you involved.
- We've been through this.
- Eighteen is too long to wait!
We had a long talk
with his pediatrician,
and we all agreed we won't
even consider surgery until
- Danny is an adult.
- I don't agree!
What do you think?
I think holding off
on a surgical procedure
is a wise decision.
- You're on her side?!
- I'm on your side.
Surgery is a big commitment.
- Your body is still changing.
- That's the point!
- I need it to stop!
- Danny, you're thirteen!
I know what I want!
- You pass as a boy.
- With breasts!
They won't let me play for
the guy's soccer team.
What if this is a phase?
You think I'm just gonna get over it?!
Yes! You might!
Look, when we get home,
we can talk some more.
Okay?
You don't believe me
Come on Danny.
No one is saying that.
She just did.
You're all the same.
- Good night, sir.
- You ordered a CT, an ECG
and an MRI for the patient in two?
Along with Kevin's racing heart,
headaches, and slurred speech,
he's also presenting with
severe abdominal pain.
The nurses say he's
vomited several times.
I looked at the MRI.
He hasn't had a stroke.
- Mm-hmm.
- You were expecting that?
Does that mean you have a theory?
There may be nothing
wrong with him at all.
Keep talking.
I think Kevin's tachycardia's
brought on by a stress reaction.
And yet he's still here.
Are you saying you want me
to send him home?
I'm saying you better have
a very good reason if you don't.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC)
(DOOR OPENING)
Are you going somewhere?
Daneesha's, remember?
You said I can sleep over.
It's Friday already?
I thought we could make
our own pizzas again
She asked for me to eat there.
Her cousins are coming over too.
That will be fun.
Will you be okay alone?
You think I need a babysitter?
(CHUCKLES) Only sometimes. How was work?
It was fine. I'll walk you over.
(DISTANT SIRENS)
(THEO): Look, the next one's on you.
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
Hey! You made it!
He's the best.
Happy birthday.
It's a Baharat. A spice
mix we use at home.
Amira toasts it.
Thanks, man. Uh Aiden Miller.
Surgeon. We were in the
same year in med school.
Bashir.
(AIDEN): Go, big guy.
Mm. You haven't changed a bit.
That is not true.
Says the guy who's wearing the
same khakis he wore to graduation
When I find pants that
fit, I stick with them!
There's nothing wrong with that.
Am I right?
- No, he's right.
- I'm right. (LAUGHING)
(LOU): You sure you
don't want something?
Early surgery tomorrow, so...
So you're not coming over later?
Don't you have your son?
He's with his mom.
Can I get a soda with lime,
please.
Oh, so y'all are gonna
make me drink alone?
- Are you okay?
- Never better.
Hey, hey, hey!
It's my favourite not-a-couple!
(MAGS LAUGHING) Wait, so
you're here together?
That means you're here together.
Right?
Are you still thinking about
your fake patient fake dying?
No, no, no. I've let that go.
Oh.
Okay, no I haven't.
But I'm also thinking about
this firefighter I saw today.
COPD. And I tried getting her to
see all the risks of ignoring it,
and she just discharged herself
to run right back into the fire.
Sounds like no one I know.
So basically you went from
obsessing over a fake patient,
to obsessing over a real one,
both of which are outside
of your control?
I gave her all the intel,
it wasn't enough to stop her.
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
(THEO): Joanie! The paramedics
came out tonight too?
I got you.
(THEO CHUCKLES)
How did I lose my wallet already?
Sign of someone
who's having a good birthday.
- Yeah.
- How old exactly?
Thirty-two.
One more year, and I've outlasted Jesus.
(LAUGHING) Hey, what do you think?
Should I...
- Should I grow a beard?
- Like Jesus?
Ha! I was thinking more
like... like a lumberjack.
Yeah! Yeah, I think
you could handle it.
Thank you.
(UPBEAT MUSIC)
One more drink, and they'll cross
over from lubricated to morose.
Is that why you're hiding?
I always hoping that a night
out will help with a tough day.
Do you want to talk about it?
I'm really better a listener.
But you're not much of a talker.
In that case...
Should we go?
(DISTANT SIRENS)
Organic...
fair trade...
dark orange.
- You remembered.
- Mm.
That's it?
That's all I want.
Mm.
Why don't you stay the night?
We don't do that.
(SOFT MUSIC)
You could leave Eric, you know?
For you?
The workaholic with a hole in his head?
Get some rest.
(SOFT MUSIC)
(PANTING)
(SIRENS)
Hey. Sorry to call
you in so early.
It's fine, Arnold, I asked you to.
What's happening?
Uh, Kevin took a turn
for the worse.
I know you said to send him home,
but he could be having
an aortic dissection,
which, if went untreated,
could be fatal.
Because of the widened
mediastinum?
And because dissection already
mimics everything I've tested for.
- Heart attack, stroke...
- Get him a CTA to confirm stat.
Put cardio-thoracics on standby.
If you're right, every second counts.
Dr. Hunter!
Paula? What, what happened?
I found him trembling
on the floor,
he was burning up! He
passed out on the way over!
Hey. Danny? Can you hear me?
Did he take anything?
He said he bought testosterone
off some guy at a gym.
Would it do that to him?
We need to get him inside.
Mike, Mike! Bring a chair!
Just take a step back.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC)
Alright...
I need a resus, stat!
Code pink! Trauma bay!
Heart rate elevated.
Hyperthermic, temp is 39 and rising.
Cooling packs.
He may have ingested some
form of amphetamine.
Start 1 mg Lorazepam.
(CLAIRE): Rate's spiking!
Temp won't stabilize!
(THEO): Normal, give me that syringe.
(MACHINES BEEPING RAPIDLY)
Can I get a flush?
Okay, okay.
(CLAIRE): 110... 106...
100... 99!
Okay, start fluids, get a CBC,
lytes, and a CK to check
if there's rhabdo.
Tell lab to rush a full tox screen.
- Okay.
- Oh, my baby!
(MOTHER CRYING)
And finally after every test that I ran,
my patient's CTA is normal.
So what's next, Dr. Hamed?
Full-body PET scan?
A course of prophylactic chemotherapy?
There is nothing physically
wrong with Kevin Gomes.
You knew that ages ago.
I could have missed something.
You've never doubted
your instinct before. Why now?
Why do you think you've
missed something?
Next time this happens,
don't keep it to yourself.
Come and talk to me.
Your labs aren't back yet,
but your vitals have stabilized.
You're doing good.
What do you care?
I care.
Your mom cares too. We all do.
If she did, she'd do something.
Your mom is scared.
I saw the way she looked
when she brought you in,
she loves you very much, Danny.
Not enough to let me have surgery.
Mastectomy is a big deal
Look at me.
What do you see?
Right.
Do you know what it's like?
I feel caught in between.
I just wanna be like
the rest of the guys.
I can't live a lie
another four years.
(SOFT MUSIC)
Are they in yet? Your results.
I haven't checked.
June, it's okay if you're
worried, you know.
- I'm fine.
- Incoming!
Woman collapsed in a fire.
That's all I know.
Female, 33, unconscious.
- (MAGS): Is she a firefighter?
- No, a civilian.
Wendy Newman, hypotensive.
Penetrating trauma to the chest.
80 on 40.
She fell through a window
during an apartment fire,
and the glass cut deep.
(MACHINES BEEPING RAPIDLY)
Pericardial effusion.
She needs a bilateral chest
tubes and a sternotomy.
- Call OR.
- Pressure's 70 over 30.
There's no time, that's a
penetrating wound to the heart.
- You're saying she needs a thoracotomy?
- She needs it now.
- I'll page Atwater.
- I've got it.
ED thoracotomies have less
than a five percent success rate
We don't control the odds, doctor.
Just have to face them.
Dr. Curtis, you can't help,
so why are you here?
(JUNE): I can help talk Mags through it.
Okay, let's do it.
- Sats are dropping!
- I'm going to bag.
(BISHOP): Now would be a good time!
(JUNE): Alright, let's get
the left arm out of the way.
Prep the chest.
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC)
Alright, so,
you're gonna make an incision
between the 5th intercostal space,
from the sternum to the bed.
Scissors.
Ready to open the chest.
(BISHOP): Alright.
Just pretend I'm Dr. Curtis.
When's the last time
you got your hands dirty?
On three.
One, two, three.
(CLAIRE): She needs blood.
O-Negative. Four units.
Activate MTP and 2 grams of TXA.
Keep talking, Dr. Curtis.
Okay, you're gonna need
to make an incision
in the pericardium from apex to base.
(BISHOP): Okay, let's do it.
(JUNE): Just medial
to the phrenic nerve.
She's arresting!
Don't think, just cut.
- Is the clamp secure?
- Mm-hmm.
- Arnold, what's the count?
- She's been down 10 seconds!
(MACHINES BEEPING)
Do you see anything?
A single cardiac wound.
I can plug it with my finger.
- Good, do it.
- (PATIENT COUGHING)
(CLAIRE): And BP's rising, 80 60.
Needle driver. 1.0 sutures.
You rolled with an imperfect
situation and you had her back.
It's good to see that when
it's not a training exercise,
you two remember what we taught you.
Good work.
(SOFT MUSIC)
Good to see you got home okay.
Hey.
Was I supposed to text you?
I'm glad we ran
into each other last night.
- I had fun.
- Me too.
It was good not talking with you.
Our family doctor called it
somatic symptom disorder.
He said Kevin can actually
feel the symptoms,
even though they're just in his head.
How long has he been like this?
It started young.
Always finding some new
thing wrong with him.
Mom and Dad would rush
him to the doctor,
but he was never really sick.
- They didn't get him help?
- He hated therapy.
Our parents did their best, but...
he only got worse after he moved out.
Are there any specific triggers?
When things change,
or he has setbacks,
it could be anything.
And then anyone who doesn't
believe him is gone.
Including you.
Why didn't you tell me
any of this before?
You said he collapsed.
What if this time,
something really was wrong?
I couldn't be the reason you
didn't look closely enough.
You saw what happened when
I tried to talk to him.
I love my brother,
and I feel so bad knowing
he's in pain, but...
The second he decides he wants help,
I'll be there to support him.
Labs came back.
The shot of testosterone you bought
was laced with an amphetamine.
It was a large dose. And
that's what caused you to OD.
Why would someone sell a kid
something so dangerous?
Guys think using it
gives them a better workout.
It doesn't.
What were you thinking?!
You won't let me start T or get surgery.
Danny, please.
Let's not get into this.
I did do some digging,
and there is a gender clinic in the city
who specializes in building action
plans for transgendered youth.
Action plans? What does that mean?
Like surgery?
There are interim options.
It's a bit late to put
you on puberty blockers,
but you don't have to do a full
cross-hormone to see an effect.
So, hormone therapy.
Which means my breasts
will stop growing?
I can refer you,
if it's something you'd
like to consider.
Please, Mom.
I want this
(SOFT MUSIC)
No more buying hormones
off the street.
I cannot go through this again, Danny.
I'm sorry.
I promise.
Okay.
We'll hear what they
have to say together,
and we'll take it from there.
I won't change my mind.
I'm not promising to change mine.
Just...
one step at a time, okay baby?
Will you be disappointed in me
if this isn't a phase?
Danny, you're my kid.
You're my son.
I love you no matter what.
You know who you are.
That's pretty amazing.
Uh...
The results are up.
I'm gonna... Can you...?
I can't. I need you to look at them.
Jesus, it's not Moby Dick.
It's all clear.
(SOFT MUSIC)
You're gonna tell me there's
nothing wrong with me,
that's why they had me get dressed.
Actually, I'm not.
You're worried about being sick,
so your body is manifesting symptoms.
No, I have a heart problem,
it's... it's real, I know it.
I know it feels real.
You're just like the rest of them!
It's all in my head!
This? Coming into
the emergency department,
isn't going to stop this from happening.
You have no idea what it's like.
I'm scared I'm gonna die all the time.
There are people
who you can speak to.
I can refer you to our staff
psychiatrist, Dr. Mitchell.
I've talked to shrinks before.
They do nothing!
Because, Kevin, you
have to want that help.
You have to accept that you need it.
- No, you are not listening!
- I'm listening.
Forget it! Just forget it!
(SIGHING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
There he is!
Ah, I'm such a lightweight.
Are you still good for later?
Listen, maybe
I didn't mention this,
but I'm married.
You told me.
She's a real estate agent.
You showed me pictures of your kids.
What does that have to do with
you coming on a ride along?
I can't today.
But thanks anyway.
Well, if you find yourself stuck
here bored some other weekend,
I usually work on Saturdays.
Offer's open.
Is he doing alright?
Your patient who wanted to transition.
Better. He still wants surgery,
but he's relieved there's a way forward.
Thank you for organizing that
referral to the gender clinic.
How does your family cope
with you being away this much?
We make it work.
You know, there's a full-time position
in Emerg pediatrics opening up.
If you want to apply, you'd
have my recommendation.
I don't know what to say,
thank you.
I'd have to discuss that with my wife.
Ah, maybe they could move here?
The kind of experience you get
at a city hospital like this,
you're not gonna find that back home.
Could be an exciting new chapter.
- Hi.
You okay?
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah, I'm just, I'm like...
I'm just, I don't know.
Heard you did
a trauma bay thoracotomy?
Yeah.
The patient's recovering in ICU.
Looks like she's gonna pull through.
Saves like that
are why we do this.
You know, my mother
never wanted me to?
Become a doctor, I mean.
I thought all parents want that.
Mine are always worried
I'll push myself too hard.
Do you?
Well, if there's any
another way to do this job,
I haven't found it.
I spent the last two days
trying to help a patient
who didn't want the
kind of help he needed.
Seems like that's going around.
(SOFT MUSIC)
(SIGHING)
(BASHIR): Did you find what you
were looking for at the library?
Yeah, I did.
I finished my homework.
- All of it?
- Yeah.
- Was it hard?
- Mm... It was okay.
Are those our things?
What happened?
- Synced and corrected by martythecrazy -
- www.addic7ed.com -