My university might never release
my medical school transcripts.
But sir, I am the doctor
I told you I was.
I'm here about your former
colleague, Khaled Abdullah.
Mr. Abdullah is wanted for
an immigration violation.
So if you see him, call me.
Bashir. Bashir.
Khaled.
Everything alright?
I have these for you.
Transcripts?
I thought you were just
going to look into them.
My friend said they
were easy to reproduce.
So I told him just go ahead.
Forgeries, corruption. That
was supposed to be behind us.
These are your grades, brother.
You earned them.
Who cares where the paper comes from.
Did you pay him for these?
Yeah, they were asking about
you at the hospital as well
- Did you tell them where I was?
- Of course not.
My claim for asylum was denied.
Can you appeal? What
if you got a lawyer?
Can I stay with you just 'til
I figure out what to do?
If it was just me, it
would be different.
But I have Amira to consider,
and if we were caught...
I understand.
I'm working overnight.
Amira's with a neighbour.
Thank you. I'll leave at dawn.
Your sister will never know I was there.
And use the transcripts, Bashir.
Nobody needs to know.
Intra-nasal foreign body removal.
- Interesting new hobby.
- Yeah. Jealous?
I'm almost done if you
want to borrow it.
Uh, no time, I'm headed
home for the night.
Ugh. Eight hours of driving
for one day at home.
Huh, somebody's hard up...
It's Abby's piano recital tomorrow.
And Melissa lets the girls sleep
in our bed when I'm gone,
so that won't be happening.
- Worth it to be with your family.
- Yeah.
Amira, she spending the night solo?
Amira? Girlfriend? Daughter?
My younger sister. She's
with the neighbours.
Dr. Hamed, by any chance,
do you speak Urdu?
No. But I think my
great-grandmother did.
Call the translator.
Do you see non-surgical patients too?
Only when it's busy, which is always,
unless my surgical attending
needs me upstairs.
Imagine they paid us by the patient?
What is the pay schedule here?
- Every third Thursday.
- When I first started,
it took 'em four weeks to
get me on the payroll.
Any chance they've gotten faster?
Do you guys know a doctor?
Dr. Hamed will take you to triage.
Actually Dr. Curtis will. Dr.
Hamed and I need a word.
Legal's up in arms about
your missing transcripts.
They won't accept that you can't
get the originals out of Aleppo.
Any chance they watched the
news in the past five years?
Apparently not.
They want to see you
before making a decision.
- A decision?
- Render judgment?
Call it what you will. They've
asked to talk to you tomorrow.
Anything in particular
they want to know?
About the Syrian doctor
who showed up out of nowhere
wielding a power drill.
I think they're gonna
want to know everything.
To them, you're just a giant
flashing neon sign that reads:
Liability. Do not proceed.
Tomorrow, 6pm,
and wear the kind of tie you wear
when your entire future
hangs in the balance.
Heading home, Dr. Bishop?
Well, I can always stick around...
Oh, no we're fine.
You've been here all day.
Wendy loves it when I insert
myself and disrupt her shifts.
I still remember when 36-hour
shifts were the expectation.
That's how I trained.
Turns out we function
better when we're awake.
Well, have fun tonight, people.
What happened with the
Blakemore can't happen again.
I'm aware you have
skills and experience,
but in order for us to move forward,
I need to be convinced that
you understand our protocols.
You don't want me seeing patients?
Only the basics. Anything
beyond that, I'm looped in.
Understood?
Cardiac arrest, pulling in now.
Cardiac arrest aren't the basics?
A kid with a fever is.
How long has Tristan been sick?
Well, he had the flu for a couple days,
but tonight things just got way worse.
What happened?
He wouldn't drink the
juice that I got him,
and then he just stopped answering me
even though his eyes were open.
So I-I don't know.
Are your parents around?
Um yeah, my dad, my dad is working.
I called him, but he
didn't answer, so...
Temp's 38. BP's 110 over 70.
Let's get his fever
down and put a line in.
IV, fluids, CVC, lytes, CRP.
Tristan? Can you hear me?
I gave him a bath to try and
cool him down, but he...
You did all the right things.
It's a good thing you brought him here.
His veins are flat due to dehydration.
It's gonna be tough getting an IV in.
Don't worry, Claire's
an expert with IVs.
You can hold his hand if you want.
Yeah. Okay.
Buddy? The doctors are gonna
help you feel better, okay?
Got it.
I'm going to call your father again,
- get him to meet you down here.
- Okay.
Alright, what do we got here?
- You ready?
- Mm-hmm.
Nice. Yeah, we're gonna
have to stitch you up.
We're also gonna need a serum
tox with an alcohol level.
- Yup.
- We... We were not drinking
That's why it reeks like beer in here.
What's your name?
Well, what's yours?
Did you, did you wanna have
dinner with me sometime?
His name is Brett.
He got hit in the head
with a lacrosse stick.
Alright, Brett, follow my finger.
So you guys like to
play lacrosse at night?
Open your mouth.
No, it's actually pledge week, so we...
Wait. Dude, that's not gonna
hurt my chances, right?
Dude, dude, shut up. You took a vow!
Uh, you took a head wound
to get into a frat?
I'm already in. I just...
caught a backswing by accident.
I definitely would've taken that
hit if it meant I'd get in.
You geniuses do realize that even a
minor head wound can be dangerous,
especially when combined
with drugs and or alcohol?
I told you, we weren't drinking.
We're a holistic frat.
No booze. No drugs.
We even meditate.
Well, you seem very enlightened.
I'll be back.
Oh, shit.
Oh!
Last night was fun.
You gonna hold the door for me too?
You're welcome.
Hi. I'm Doctor Leblanc. What
seems to be the problem today?
I don't know why I'm here.
I'm not hurt, as far as I can tell.
Okay, uh, what is the
last thing you remember?
They told me a cab driver brought me in.
But I remember where I
took the cab, or why.
I don't even know my own name.
And you don't have any ID on you?
Wallet, phone?
I don't know the password to unlock it.
What kind of person leaves
their house without a wallet?
Okay. Um, look at my finger.
Well, doesn't seem like
you've been drinking.
In any other case, I'd take
a complete medical history,
but obviously that's not an option.
Do you have any idea why
this is happening to me?
Uh, head trauma, even mild,
can cause memory loss,
but your pupils aren't dilated,
so concussion's unlikely.
Could be lifestyle related. A
substance you ingested, maybe
Do you think you can help me?
Yeah, well, we'll run some tests,
and narrow down the diagnoses.
If anything comes back
to you, you let us know.
I wasn't home when they brought him in.
Max was worried. He's a
great older brother,
but sometimes he's a
little overprotective.
What, I wasn't...
Dad, you know he's really sick, right?
Dr. Hamed, this is Jared Abott.
He would like to take his son home.
- Where's his fever?
- 39 now.
That's up from before.
Sir, taking him home is not a good idea.
He's been unresponsive
and has a high fever.
We need to give him antibiotics.
How do we know the fever
isn't a reaction to
something that you have given him here?
- Dad, no, I...
- He had a fever before
I took him in. That's why he's here.
I don't want him taking
unnecessary drugs.
Tristan doesn't react well to them.
How would you know? You
never give him any.
Sir, this could be more
than a simple flu.
We don't know what's causing
your son's fever to spike.
It could be a serious infection.
- He's not vaccinated.
- Max!
They have to know, Dad!
- Is that true?
- Which vaccinations is he missing?
All of them.
- Synced and corrected by martythecrazy -
- www.addic7ed.com -
We must shift Tristan Abbot in
negative pressure isolation.
Gloves, gowns, masks on
everyone, staff or family,
until we know what he has.
You're back?
Unvaccinated child with
a mystery illness?
More interesting than my flat screen.
I know that look.
She's already writing
a paper in her head.
So, what's the case?
Seemingly healthy male,
no idea who he is and no
ability to retain new memories
Think it could be
Transient Global Amnesia?
- What about a concussion?
- No headache, dizziness, nausea.
No evidence of a fall or head trauma.
Order a tox screen and CT just to
rule out anything more serious.
He's out for both right now.
Usually with TGA, a patient
still knows their name.
Well, studies show some
cases are more acute.
Could even be brought on by stress.
So should I call neurology?
No, they'll only come down
if the CT shows something.
With TGA, we're told to just
wait until he remembers,
or someone comes looking for him.
The Abbott boy's fever is still holding.
The father wants to know
when we're discharging him.
Of course he does.
Get set up for the lumbar puncture.
With your permission, I'd like to do it.
I will do it.
Page me when you're ready.
Get to work, both of you.
Most first year don't get to do
spinal on their third shift.
I may be a first year here, but
this is not my third shift.
Okay.
Do you see a lot of
unvaccinated children?
More than we should.
People afraid of side
effects, primarily autism.
That study was retracted.
Yeah, and a tonne of misinformation
is taking its place.
Are there antivaxxers in Syria?
People there are desperate for vaccines.
We fight to get them into the country.
The spinal needles
you're giving Tristan...
Explain to me why you have to do this.
We need to rule out
life-threatening infections
like meningitis or encephalitis.
And the blood tests you've
already done can't do that?
There's a limit to what
blood work can tell us.
Is it going to hurt him?
We'll freeze up the skin
to minimize any pain,
and make sure it's over
as quickly as possible.
Max got one vaccination
when he was a baby.
It left him paralyzed for a week.
Half his little face was frozen.
Reactions like that are rare,
and almost never serious.
Until they are.
We were lucky that he bounced back.
After that, we were done with it.
The body builds its own immunity.
Then neither of your
sons are vaccinated?
Mr. Abbott. We only
want to help your son.
We'll be as non-invasive
as we can moving forward.
Their mother was a natural with this.
Together, we got Max through
colds, flus, even measles.
We lost her suddenly in a car accident.
Tristan wouldn't even remember her.
I'm sorry to hear that.
Is everything ready, Dr. Hamed?
- Mm-hm.
- I'll insert the spinal needle.
Hello. I'm Dr. Leblanc.
A taxi brought you in and you
couldn't remember who you are.
And we've already met.
How can I not remember a
single thing about myself?
Well, we do know a few things.
Your imaging and blood work aren't
showing any significant abnormalities.
So we know you're basically healthy.
There's no pill you can give me?
Jar my brain into recalling some facts?
I wish there was.
Give me your arm.
That's quite a scar.
Huh.
It's weird...
A stranger putting your life
under the microscope this way.
Well, how about we widen the field?
- You can cross-examine mine.
- Are you serious?
Okay. Um...
Young doctor starting out?
Entry level BMW,
a tiny perfect condo
and, uh...
and a couple cats you
rescued from the shelter.
Couple cats? Now I'm offended.
I still live in my studio walk-up.
Turn around for me please?
You don't want to put down roots?
I'd rather spend on experiences.
Live while there's time.
Toussez deux fois?
Well, we just found
out you speak French.
- I do?
- Yeah.
You responded to my
request, en français.
The only thing you need to know
about me is that I don't give up.
And I love my car.
Hey.
So, uh...
Couple more hours, then we
can release your friend.
Is there anyone you can
call to wait with him?
You could go home.
No one even supposed to
know what we're doing,
so if I leave then I'll never get in.
Ethan.
I mean, is it... is it really
worth demeaning yourself
just to be accepted by a
collection of entitled assholes?
I'm here on scholarship, and...
half the alumni get the
kind of finance jobs
I want after business school, so...
Yeah. It is.
Wow. You'll really take
any excuse, won't you?
You're not happy to see me?
You need to be able to trust your staff.
I do. I only hire the best.
Then why are you back here instead
of getting the rest you need?
Sound of an empty house
is too loud for you?
It's my department, Claire. I
can come and go as I please.
But it's touching that
you worry about me.
I'm too busy to worry about you.
Can't decide?
My dad says it's all chemicals.
He may have a point about that.
He's not happy with me.
I know.
But you did the right thing
by telling us about Tristan.
You know, he...
He talks about getting
me through measles...
as if him and my mom were heroes.
You know? But it wasn't
like that for me.
At all.
I never told them, but I...
I was so afraid that I was gonna die.
And, I don't know...
You know, after my mom...
it's just gotten even harder
to talk to him, so...
I won't tell if you won't.
Theo, I thought you
were with your family.
Made it halfway home.
Atwater wants all her
pediatric resources close by.
Well, I guess she just doesn't trust me.
You mind taking a listen to that?
Onset of stridor, right?
It's faint but it's definitely there.
Open his mouth.
- Whoa, that's...
- a pseudo-membrane.
If it grows, it could
obstruct his airway.
Diphtheria.
- I didn't think that existed here.
- It shouldn't.
There have been two or three
cases in the past decade,
but it's extremely rare.
- I've never seen it.
- I have.
And even people with
immunity can be carriers
We need to start treatment now.
There's an antitoxin.
Which we don't stock due to vaccines.
I'll get someone from
Public Health on the phone
but they'll have to mix a compound.
It's unlikely we'll get anything
until tomorrow afternoon.
Do we have that long?
If the membrane is already forming,
his airway will be compromised.
We'll watch him closely and
keep pushing antibiotics.
'Til then, we just need to
keep him hydrated and on O2.
We need to inform the father.
He's put this whole ward at risk.
Alright, field trip's over.
If you vomit, come back. If
you're dizzy, come back.
No alcohol, mm?
And no sports.
And you. Ethan.
You think you can help
him stick to that?
Ethan? You with me buddy?
Ethan? Ethan?
Ethan! You okay?
What did he take, Brett?
I need help over here!
He doesn't have a pulse. We
have to get him to trauma.
On three. One, two, three.
- What did he take, Brett?
- I don't know, I swear!
We have a cardiac arrest!
Claire! Claire, call Atwater.
Get everyone to trauma!
We need Atwater, and we need Leblanc.
We did a tox screen but
only on the injured one.
Let's get a line going. Push epi.
Let me know when you've got a read.
Come on...
Pulse check.
Mm-mm.
He's in V-Fib, we need to defibrillate!
Defib, 200 Jules.
Brett, what did he take?!
- Uh...
- Charging. Pads on.
- Ready.
- Everyone clear!
Resume compressions.
- Brett, what'd he take?!
- It-It wasn't dangerous.
One amp epi.
Whatever it was, he did it
to impress you, alright?
So if you don't tell us
now, Ethan is gonna die!
Soy sauce. He drank soy sauce.
We make all the new pledges do it.
If they don't, they get
the lacrosse stick.
Most people just drink a
few sips and take a whack,
but Ethan drank the whole bottle.
- Hypernatremia?
- Made worse by alcohol consumption.
The sodium is pulling water
from his organs and his brain.
You can fix him, right?
Start an infusion of D5W.
I'll take over compressions.
Doctor Hamed?
Bash.
Rhythm?
Asystole.
Does anyone have any other suggestions
on how to save this patient?
Time, Dr. Curtis.
- Time of death, 4:17 AM.
- What?
We can't save them if they
don't tell us what's wrong.
You had a busy night?
We made dinners for the whole week.
Hey, can you use your
key, I forgot mine.
Are we going to have to leave?
It says rent past due.
No, no, this is not a big deal, Amira.
What about Pavel's daughter Nadia?
I could offer to babysit.
I've done it before. If we
need money, I can help!
Your job is going to school
and learning English.
Okay? I'll go talk to Pavel right
now and sort it out. Okay?
It's not... Here. Take this.
Go.
You could have just talked
to me directly, Pavel.
Amira saw the notice.
Landlord asks me, I ask you.
I just need a little more time.
Who was the stranger with your keys?
Just a friend. I'm allowed
to have visitors.
Visitors come when you're at home.
Your lease is for two people.
Look Bashir, you know I like you. Okay?
I'm just trying to keep
you out of trouble.
Okay. You'll have the rent tomorrow.
My brother says it's okay,
but if we have to leave, I
would not see you anymore.
I would miss you.
Everything okay in here?
We're fine. You barely slept.
I know. I have to go
back to the hospital.
Are you ready to go?
- Hi, Daneesha.
- Hi.
We did everything we
could to save that boy.
I just had to tell that kid's
parents their only son just died
trying to get into a frat.
Stupid, meaningless way to die.
It doesn't make it any easier
when they die for a reason.
For those of you just coming
on shift, let me reiterate.
We have an active case of diphtheria
in an unvaccinated child.
If you work here, you're
already inoculated.
If someone you know
isn't, they should be.
We're running a vaccination clinic,
Rhoda will have the details.
The child is being kept,
under strict isolation
so make sure you follow procedure.
If you have had direct
contact, see Claire
for cultures and
prophylactic antibiotics.
Dr. Hunter is primary,
and Dr. Hamed, who has
actually treated this disease,
is a good resource. Make
sure that we use him.
- Yes?
- Mm-hmm.
Alright. Dismissed.
Legal in an hour, you ready?
Hmm. What was that for?
Nothing.
You sure?
My place later?
Um, if Tristan's awake, could you
just tell him I'm right outside?
I know it must be hard not
being able to help him, but...
Your brother and your
father need you healthy.
Is it true that he could die?
I don't think my dad can
handle losing somebody else.
We're doing everything we can to
make sure that doesn't happen.
Mm?
- The antitoxin's ready.
- What's next?!
All you people have been doing
is pumping him full of God knows
what, and it isn't helping.
We've been keeping him on antibiotics,
waiting for the right
medication to arrive.
Now that it has, we're able
to target his infection.
You're telling me this one will help?
I'm asking you to trust us.
What are you doing here?
You're not on tonight.
I know how to figure
out who John Doe is.
I figured out the scar on his
elbow was from a UCL replacement.
The surgeon probably used a
tendon from a tissue bank.
Anyway, the point is, only a
really skilled baseball player
would ever get a surgery like that.
And, you know, like a
pitcher with prospects.
And we know he speaks French, so
according to the age of the scar
he could've played AAA in some
affiliated minor league...
Mags. Mags. Stop. He's gone.
He's discharged.
He got his memory back?
Yeah. A few hours after
you left this morning.
Wow.
Well. I guess that's good.
I just, uh... was I right? Who is he?
Uh, Brian something?
He remembered his name, he called
his wife, she came to get him.
That's all I know..
Okay.
Well I can stick around, looks like
you might need the help, so...
It's your day off.
Go do whatever it is you
do when you're not here.
Do we have to lower the dosage?
We'll slow the infusion
and desensitize him.
And if that's not enough?
What's going on? What's
happening to him?
He's having an allergic
reaction to the medication.
It's a side effect, but
one we can manage.
You need to stop. Don't
give him any more.
This is exactly what
I was worried about!
Tristan is in very critical condition.
His throat is closing. He can't
fight this off on his own.
You said that you'd help him. All
you're doing is hurting him!
You're the one who hurt him.
By leaving him vulnerable to this.
All I did was try to protect him!
But you didn't!
And if you stand in our way
now, Tristan is going to die,
and it will be your fault.
This place is a madhouse.
I've been on the phone all day.
Want to switch jobs for an hour?
I spoke with Tristan's home daycare,
Public Health notified his community.
No one else the kid came into contact
with seems to be symptomatic.
I heard you had a few choice
words with the father.
I find that having an outlet
helps keep the frustration
from boiling over.
- What's yours?
- Boxing.
Sometimes bourbon?
You good?
If someone with very few resources
needed a place to stay.
Would you have advice for him too?
It's not for me.
Right.
Um... Any other info to go on?
The details aren't really mine to share.
Does this person have a
history of violence?
Substance abuse?
Give it time.
Any place I find on short notice
is sure to turn him on to both.
I have to get going.
- I'll get back to you.
- Thank you.
- Hey.
- Labs are back on the Abbott kid.
- Which one.
- The older brother.
They screened for diphtheria but
you ordered a broader panel?
Max.
You have antibodies that
your brother doesn't,
but I think you already knew that.
It's a gown for the quarantine room.
If you want to be with
Tristan you can be,
but your father's gonna figure it out.
I know you think he's...
stupid and ignorant.
But he's not.
He's just stubborn, and...
he's lost without my mom.
Tristan needs me, so...
I'm gonna go in there and be with him.
What are you talking about?
You are not going in there.
I got vaccinated, Dad.
Like, the day I turned 16.
You and Mom decided for me.
And I didn't agree with your
choice so I made my own.
You hid this from me?
I had to!
You were wrong, Dad.
Dr. Hamed? We need you in there, now.
His airway's nearly blocked.
Oh, God.
His neck's too swollen. Bag him.
- He needs a cric.
- Now. We can't wait for an OR.
Tristan needs an operation immediately
that will allow him to breathe
through a hole in his neck.
- Dad.
- Please, save him.
Okay. We'll come and get
you as soon as we're done.
Go ahead. We work as a team, here.
I can't feel any landmarks.
The neck is too swollen.
Make a large vertical incision and
I'll talk you through the anatomy.
Claire.
Palpate through the tissue 'til
you feel the cric membrane.
Careful, it'll be small
on a child his age.
- I feel it.
- Make a horizontal stab incision.
- I'm in.
- Sats are 75% and falling.
Keep going, Dr. Hamed.
Use your finger to confirm you're
in the trachea, then thread.
- I'm feeling resistance.
- BP's crashing.
- He's going to arrest.
- Stay focused.
It's likely in the subcutaneous
tissues, don't force it.
Use your finger to confirm
you're in the right place.
- Bash. Tell me what you need.
- The bougie isn't threading.
There it goes. Railroad the tube.
Sats are climbing. He's stabilizing.
Well done, everyone.
I'll go tell his father.
We understand that you completed
medical school in 2011.
Then specialized as trauma surgeon
and emergency medicine doctor
practicing at various state
and field hospitals in Syria,
before moving onto a clinic
in a refugee camp in Turkey.
I thought I'd sit in.
Oh, we were just discussing Dr.
Hamed's work history.
Mm. He has more experience
than a few of our attendings.
What happened after Turkey?
- I came here.
- Without your original transcripts.
I have documents proving my identity.
But not your credentials.
Without those, the hospital
assumes a serious risk.
One we can't afford.
How can we be sure
you're truly qualified?
I suppose you can't.
No actually you can.
Because I hired him.
I'm sitting here because of him.
With respect Dr. Bishop,
that's not enough.
I'm not diminishing anything
he did for you but...
He just performed an
emergency cricothyrotomy
on a kid who has a disease that...
shouldn't even exist here.
Even still.
This is about us needing a paper trail
that proves he is who he says he is.
They targeted doctors.
In Syria.
Especially ones who smuggled vaccines
into the country to try to prevent
typhoid, dysentery, diphtheria.
It's simple.
The state controls the universities.
And I am an enemy of the State.
There is no paper trail
because of who I am.
Let's be clear.
What you're saying is that you
can't get your transcripts
because you're an enemy
of the state in Syria.
You know that could expose us
to all kind of scrutiny that...
No, no, hold on.
That's not what we're saying.
Dr. Hamed and I are going to
pause and think this through.
Ty, we'll circle back to you soon. Yeah?
You've opened up a real can of
worms with that confession of you.
Well, it's the truth.
Some truths are better left unsaid.
Either way, both of us
are out on a limb now.
Tristan's responding well to the cric.
- Great job.
- You too.
You're, uh, you're back tomorrow?
Yeah, then I got two days off.
I'm not on tomorrow, so
I'll take your shift.
Go get an extra day with your family.
- Really?
- Mm-hmm.
Thanks, man.
He's stable now.
We're going to continue a
modified treatment regimen,
but he's going to recover.
I almost lost him.
But you didn't.
Max is so mad at me.
There's still time to fix that.
And Max is a great kid.
So you are doing something right.
Hey.
I never wanted to lie to you.
I'm sorry I made you
feel like you had to.
I love you, son.
Hi!
- I thought it was your day off.
- Yeah!
Mm-hmm, yeah, it is, it is.
It's just, um...
I just, I focus better in here, so...
This might be the strangest
thing I've heard all day.
Bye, Bash.
My building super saw you.
Is he going to tell anyone?
You know, this isn't a
safe place for you anyway.
I know.
It's a shelter you can go to.
That's all I can do right now.
Maybe we shouldn't talk for a while.
You're a good friend, Bashir.
You said you've babysat before.
I didn't ask you when.
After Mama and Papa had to send
me to live with the cousins
we went to the camp in Turkey.
There were many kids younger than me.
Warda and I used to take turns
watching them all the time.
You and Warda were close.
You must miss her.
You weren't there, so you wouldn't
have known about the babysitting.
Now I do.
Amira, we're okay.
You'd tell me if we weren't?
I promise.
- Synced and corrected by martythecrazy -
- www.addic7ed.com -